□我們就是這樣做的□
□This is how we do it□
本字幕由  獨立字幕組   原創譯制
更多字幕請訪問 idpsub.webflow.io
翻譯 & 校對：Sean Zhang
關注新浪微博@獨立字幕組
特效：Sean Zhang
歌詞時間軸 & 註釋：水貂
總監：Sean Zhang
環球影業出品
獨立字幕組
IDPSUB
歡迎回來，各位阿卡貝拉狂熱粉絲
Welcome back, a cappella enthusiasts.
我是約翰史密斯
My name is John Smith,
坐在我左面的這位是
and sitting here to my left
蓋爾阿伯內西邁卡登范貝格爾
is Gail Abernathy-McCadden-Feinberger.
約翰，大家會記住我的名字的
Oh, this one's gonna stick, John.
-,哦，希望如此吧 -他們會的
- Well, you saved the Jew for last. - I did. I did.
您現在在收聽的是《一起阿卡貝拉》
You're listening to Let's Talk-Appella,
世界第一個阿卡貝拉播客
the world's premiere downloadable a cappella podcast.
我們現在正在首都華盛頓的肯尼的中心
We are coming to you live from the nation's capital,
為你直播巴頓大學貝拉合唱團的精彩演出
where the Barden University Bellas are about to rock the historic Kennedy Center.
天啊，這些女孩真的打破了一切
Boy, these girls have broken down
在她們成功路上的阻撓，不是嗎？蓋爾。
every single barrier in their path, haven't they, Gail?
沒錯，約翰
Absolutely, John.
正是她們贏得了第一個全國女子
The first all-female group to win a national title,
三次成功衛冕，現在
three-time defending champs, and now, here they are,
她們將要為美國總統慶祝生日
performing for the President of the United States on his birthday.
哇！這對於那些長得不夠漂亮
Wow! What an inspiration
而無法成為啦啦隊隊長的女孩來說是多麼鼓舞的事
to girls all over the country who are too ugly to be cheerleaders.
□我們歡呼的時候他們說我們顛了□
□They say you're a freak when we're having fun□
《We Got the World》- Icona Pop（專輯：Icona Pop）2012
□我們傳播愛的時候他們說我們嗑藥了□
□They say you must be high when we're spreading love□
□我們只是活在當下從不止步□
□We're just living life and we never stop□
□因為我們擁有這個世界□
□We got the world□
□我們擁有這個世界□
□We got the world world world world world□
□這個世界□
□World world world world world□
□所有東西都在旋轉，我要倒下了□
□It's going down, I'm yelling timber□
《Timber》- Pitbull & Ke$ha（單曲專輯：Timber）2013
□你最好動起來，你最好跳起了□
□You better move, you better dance□
□為你營造一個終身難忘夜晚□
□Let's make a night you won't remember□
□而我正是那個讓你不會忘記的人□
□I'll be the one you won't forget□
這是隊長貝卡米切爾
Here's Beca Mitchell, leader of the group.
看看這一些閃閃發光的閃片
Look at these sequins and sparkles.
她們真是一步也停不下來，活力無限啊
Oh, my! Their feet just don't stop moving.
□越厲害的人越難倒下□
□The bigger they are, the harder they fall□
□那個自以為是的傢伙灰溜溜地逃走了□
□These bigiddy boys are diggidy dogs□
□我像麥粒一樣，脫得一絲不掛□
□I have 'em like Miley Cyrus, clothes off□
□像在羅斯頓狂抖屁股，Timber□
□Twerking in their bras and thongs, timber□
□狂歡小城，甩起屁股，Timber□
□Crazy town, booty up, timber□
□這就是我們喜歡戰爭的部分，Timber□
□That's the way we like to war? Timber□
□我在它上面撒油□
□I'm slicker than an oil spill□
□她說她不會怎麼做，不過我打賭她一定會，Timber□
□She say she won't, but I bet she will, timber□
聽說弗倫西婭富恩特斯剛剛拿到了美國綠卡，約翰
Florencia Fuentes just earned her green card, John.
不然她就要跟著這個後空翻
She may have to do that backflip
翻回墨西哥去啦
right back over the fence into Mexico.
我覺得她是危地馬拉人
I think she's Guatemalan.
哦，管她哪裡來的
Oh, none of that matters.
舞台上的表演太精彩了真是應接不暇，我都不知道要看哪裡好
There is so much happening on stage, I don't even know where to look.
在我年輕的時候我們只是唱唱歌
Back in my day, we put on our blazers and we just sang.
唱到高興的時候也許打打響指
We maybe snapped our fingers if we were feeling frisky.
□從此岸到彼岸□
□From sea to shining sea□
《America The Beautiful》- 美國愛國歌曲 （大意：以同胞的愛加冕汝之善行，從此岸到彼岸）
□我像毀滅球一樣的闖入□
□I came in like a wrecking ball□
《Wrecking Ball》- Miley Cyrus（專輯：Bangerz）2013
□在任何一段感情，我從沒有闖入的如此艱難□
□I never hit so hard in love□
哇！又一個驚喜
Whoa! Another surprise!
一個豐滿的女孩坐在垂下來的絲帶上
An overweight girl dangling from the ceiling.
－誰沒有過這樣的夢想？－很多所有人都有過
- Who hasn't had that dream? - Lots of us.
□你做過的一切已經毀滅了我□
□All you ever did was wreck me□
□我像毀滅球一樣的闖入□
□I came in like a wrecking ball□
□我緊閉我的雙眼，不停搖擺□
□Yeah, I just closed my eyes and swung□
□你做過的一切已經毀滅了我□
□Left me crouching in a blaze and fall□
□你做過的一切毀滅了我□
□All you ever did was wreck me□
□沒錯，你毀了我□
□Yeah, you, you wrecked me□
不!
No!
- 她並沒有穿底褲 - 哦，我的天啊！
- Okay, she has no underwear on. - Oh, my God.
我們遇到了一個緊急情況
We have a commando situation.
舞台上突發了一個緊急情況
There is a commando situation on stage!
誰能管管這個
Who is on top of this?
- 哪種人... - 天啊！
- What kind of person... - Holy cow!
- 快把她拉上去，她正在轉過來 - 快把她拉上去
- Take her back up. She's turning. - Pull her up already!
- 她正在轉過來 ，保重 - 不！
- She's turning. Brace yourselves. - No.
她正在轉過來，她正在轉過來！
She's coming. She's coming!
接著看或者閉上眼睛，請自行選擇
Avert your eyes, or take it all in! Make your choice!
沒有人想看她的正面
Not the front! Nobody wants to see the front!
哦，不！！
Oh, no!
生日快樂，總統先生
Happy birthday, Mr. President.
一位來自澳大利亞自稱「胖艾米」的歌手在昨天晚上
The Australian singer who calls herself "Fat Amy"
肯尼迪中心的表演中，用她的「下面」給了總統一份
gave the President a birthday gift from down under
終身難忘的生日禮物
during last night's celebration held at the historic Kennedy Center.
如果你不知道我說的「下面」指什麼
In case you're wondering what I mean by "down under," Chip,
我指的是她的「逼」
I'm talking about her...
她讓總統看了她的「逼」
She showed her... to the President.
完
美
音
調
巴頓貝拉合唱團吸引了無數目光
All eyes were on the a cappella singers, the Barden Bellas.
連續三次的衛冕阿卡貝拉全國賽
...three-time defending a cappella national champions,
可以說是非常了不起的
which is a real thing, apparently.
即使政府部門排除了這是一次恐怖襲擊的可能
Although authorities have ruled out terrorism as a motive,
巴頓貝拉公開聲明這次是一次事故
the Bellas claim the mishap was merely an accident
並公開道歉
and issued an apology.
我對我所造成一切深感抱歉
I am deeply sorry for the upset that I have caused.
我覺得我已經在絲綢的摩擦中
I feel that I have already received punishment enough
受到了足夠的懲罰了
in the form of silk burn.
請看第三證物
Exhibit C.
不不不不！別脫！
No, no, no!
這一切真是不堪入目
It's filth.
這是讓女人當歌手導致文明衰退
Women who sing are just another example
的又一典例
of cultural decay, due to loose morals.
我覺得她是故意
Not wearing underwear
-不穿內褲的 -嗯
- seems kind of intentional to me. - Mmm.
你要麼選擇穿或選擇不穿
Yeah, you either choose to wear underwear, or you don't wear underwear.
這是我每天都要做的選擇
It's a choice I make every day.
直到今天，我覺得唱阿卡貝拉
You know, until today, I thought singing a cappella
才是最羞恥的事
was the most embarrassing thing you could do.
她們一直都很棒
Normally, that group is on point,
但是昨天晚上，她們失常了
and last night, they were off-point,
跑調，一下子從天上掉了下來
off-key, and then on the floor.
這是國家的恥辱啊
It's a national disgrace.
我寧願搭上總統的豪車
Yeah, but I'd rather be in that limo ride home with the President.
轉到總統面前
Cut to the real President, he'd be like,
說：「這個婊有點過分了」
"That... was off the hook!"
巴頓大學
克洛伊，冷靜，這只是一個小錯誤而已
Chloe, chill out. It was a mistake.
他們又不會把我們當作巫婆燒死
They're not gonna burn us for witchcraft.
沒錯，但是現在國家阿卡貝拉組織
No, but the National A Cappella Association
正在找院長談話，誰知道會發生什麼事
is in there talking to the dean about us, and who knows what's gonna happen?
我們三次衛冕
We won three championships.
無論發生什麼，我們都會沒事的
Whatever happens in there, we're gonna be fine.
也許是時候該想想別的事了
Maybe it's time to think about other stuff.
其他事情？
What other stuff?
你知道的，學習，工作，以後的生活
You know, school, jobs, life.
這個樂團就是我的人生
This group is my life.
我故意掛了三次俄國文學
I've intentionally failed Russian Lit three times
才成為一名貝拉成員
so I could be a Bella.
這是有史以來發生在我們身上最糟糕的事了
This is the worst thing that's ever happened to us. Ever.
你知道嗎，在我來到巴頓大學之前
You know, before coming to Barden,
我得了七年的痢疾
I had diarrhea for seven years.
但是，沒錯，這是糟糕透了
But yes, this is terrible.
院長準備好和你們談話了，蕩婦們
The dean is ready for you tramps.
哦，天
Oh, jeez.
女士們
Ladies,
你們已經把巴頓大學的名譽
you have dragged the good name
拖到了下水溝
of Barden University into the gutter.
而且你們也讓這些人非常失望
And you've really upset these people
我已經忘記了他們的名字了
whose names I've already forgotten.
你們在總統面前表現
Your little southern exposure in front of our Commander-in-Chief
已經在阿卡貝拉屆造成了無法挽回的損傷
has irreparably damaged the entire institution of a cappella.
你們搞砸了
Just blew it up.
資金在縮水，投資人在撤資
Funding is drying up, sponsors are pulling out.
-嗯 -不幸的是，我們必須給出處罰
- Mmm-hmm. - Unfortunately, an example must be made.
因此主管部門決定
It is the decision of this governing body
貝拉樂團被禁止參加
that the Bellas are hereby suspended
-院校級別的比賽 -什麼？
- from competing at the collegiate level. - What?
所有關於你們禁賽的文件都在這裡了
The terms of your suspension are laid out in this document.
-很抱歉，但是你們沒有希望了 -嘿
- I'm sorry, but it's over. - Hi.
好了，你們能不能講點道理？
Okay, can we be reasonable?
胖艾米已經道過歉了，這只是一個事故
Fat Amy apologized. This was an accident.
這是事故嗎？
Was it?
我們不能進行我們的巡演了？
You're taking us off of our victory tour?
那誰要在狗狗杯唱國歌啊？
Who's gonna sing the national anthem at the Puppy Bowl?
你們的巡演資格將會由歐洲冠軍取代
You're being replaced by the European champions.
一個由專業歌手組成的德國樂團
A German group of total professionals.
而且他們穿著底褲
In other words, they're gonna keep their pants on.
所以說我們不能繼續比賽，和進行巡演了麼？
So we can't defend our title and we can't tour?
而且你們不能夠再進行招新
And you can't hold any auditions.
我們不需要你們像真菌一樣瘋狂生長
We don't need your ranks to grow like a fungus.
所以說就這樣了？
Oh, so that's it, then?
所以說可以說貝拉就這樣完了？
So, basically, the Bellas are over?
聽著，女士們
Look, ladies,
這個處罰打擊到了你們，我很抱歉
I'm sorry that this disciplinary action has shocked you.
特別是你們已經是高年級的學生了
Especially since you're all seniors.
但事實是，你們只是女人而已
But the truth is, you're just women.
沒錯
No.
-然後你們很快將會懷孕 -嗯
- And you'll all be pregnant soon. - Mmm.
媽，我要遲到了
Mom, I'm late.
這是新生介紹，我現在真的要走了
It's orientation. You gotta let me go.
我不能這樣做
Oh, I can't.
我就是做不到
I just can't do it.
媽媽，你可以的
Mom, you can do it.
我的獨生女要離我而去
My only daughter, leaving the nest.
如果你現在離開我
If you leave me now
就是奪走了我的一部分
You'll take away the biggest part of me
－媽？ －你要我停下來？
- Mom. - You want me to stop?
或者我可以繼續唱下去
Or I could keep singing!
我都不知道沒了你唱歌，我該怎麼活下去
No, I don't know how I'm gonna get by without your spontaneous singing.
哦，親愛的，你會愛上這個地方的
Oh, honey, you're gonna love this place.
答應我你會打電話給我
Just promise you'll call.
還有，親愛的，不要害怕展現自我
Oh, and, honey, don't be afraid to express yourself.
還有不要像他們一樣在耳朵上帶上一些紐扣
And not with those weird buttons they wear in their earlobes.
－除非你要...... －媽媽，行了
- Unless you're gonna get a job... - Mom, slow down.
我不會做什麼瘋狂的事的
I'm not gonna do anything crazy.
我只寫我的歌然後加入阿卡貝拉樂團
I'm just gonna write my songs and join an a cappella group.
不是任意的阿卡貝拉樂團
Not just any a cappella group.
貝拉樂團才是你的目標
The Bellas are an institution.
我在貝拉的時光......
My days as a Bella were the best...
是你的度過最好的時光
Best days of your life.
我已經等不及成為她們的一員了
I know. And I can't wait to be one.
除非她們不接受我，媽媽
Unless they don't take me, Mom.
哦，不親愛的，她們會接受你的
Oh, no, honey, they're gonna take you.
因為我，你天生就是貝拉樂團的一員
Thanks to me, you were born into it.
然後我是你的母親
And then I'm gonna be your mother...
也是你的姐妹
And your sister
真肉麻，好了
Gross. Okay.
我人生的下一階段
All right, the next phase of my life
開始了
begins.
等等
Hold on.
這裡沒有任何東西可以剝奪掉我們國家冠軍的稱號
There is nothing in here that strips us of our national title.
如果我們是冠軍的話
And if we're still reigning champs,
我們將會以美國代表的身份被邀請
then we are automatically invited to represent America
參加今年春天的國際比賽
at the World Championships this spring.
哦，是啊，四年一屆的阿卡貝拉世界錦標賽
Ah, yes, the World Championships of A Cappella,
來自於全球各地的樂隊相互競爭
where, every four years,
成為冠軍
groups from around the globe compete for world domination.
哦，抱歉，我只是覺得我應該跟上潮流
I'm sorry. I just feel like I always have to be on, you know.
是的，這樣，女士們
Yeah. Yeah. Well, look, ladies,
我們不能阻止你們參加世界錦標賽
we can't stop you from going to the Worlds competition.
但是這對這件事並沒有什麼幫助
It's not gonna help your case here.
一點都沒有
Not at all.
要是我們贏了呢？
What if we win it?
要是你們贏了？
What if you win it?
就你們？
Like, you...
你們要打敗別的樂團？
You out-perform the other groups?
你是怎麼把如此大的夢想裝進這麼小的身體裡的？
How do you fit such big dreams in such a small body?
要是你們贏了？
What if you win it?
永遠不會
Never.
要是你們贏了？
What if you win it?
－對，如果我們贏了，那我們會被解禁嗎？－當然
- Yeah. If we win, will you reinstate us? - Sure.
但是美國隊從來沒有贏過
But no American team has ever won.
因為他們都討厭我們
That's because they hate us.
整個世界
The whole world.
整個世界都討厭我們
The whole world hates us.
討厭我們
Hate us.
你們好，新生們
Hello, fresh-persons!
歡迎來到巴頓大學
Welcome to Barden University!
下去吧，巴頓騎士
Okay! The Barden Knight.
沒有人想看到你，好了
Okay, get off the stage. No one cares about you. All right.
你做了一個重大但是很廉價的選擇
You have made a great choice, and a cheap one.
哦耶，巴頓
Yay, Barden!
今天，我們為你們準備了一個特別的表演
We have a very special performance for you guys today.
下面有請巴頓大學的驕傲和歡樂來源
The pride and joy of Barden University,
麻煩鬼樂團
the Treblamakers!
謝謝，謝謝，謝謝
Thank you! Thank you, thank you.
我們是麻煩鬼樂團
We are the Treblemakers.
我是傑西，我們要給大家帶來的是一首阿卡貝拉
I'm Jesse, and this is a cappella.
開始啦！
Let's do this!
嘿，麻煩鬼們
Hey yo, Trebles!
《Lollipop》- Mika（專輯：Life in Cartoon Motion）2007
□用力吃你的棒棒糖□
□Sucking too hard on your lollipop□
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
□用力吃你的棒棒糖□
□Sucking too hard on your lollipop□
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
□用力吃你的棒棒糖□
□Sucking too hard on your lollipop□
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
□有一天，我和媽媽一起散步□
□I went walking with my momma one day□
□她提醒我人們說的那些話□
□When she warned me what people say□
□漫漫度過你的人生直到發現真愛□
□Live your life until love is found□
□否則愛情會把你吞下讓你受傷□
□Cause loves gonna get you down□
□看看隔壁的那個女孩□
□Take a look at the girl next door□
□她是個愛玩遊戲的風流女人□
□She's a player and a downright bore□
□耶酥也為她放慢了腳步,她卻想要更多□
□Jesus loves her but she wants more□
□哦,壞女孩會讓你受傷□
□Oh, bad girls get you down□
□大聲唱出來□
□Sing it!□
□用力吃你的棒棒糖□
□Sucking too hard on your lollipop
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
□用力吃你的棒棒糖□
□Sucking too hard on your lollipop
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
□說愛，說愛□
□Say love, say love□
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
□說愛，說愛□
□Say love, say love□
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
□有人給點低音嗎□
□Someone, drop some bass□
□愛愛愛，說愛，愛愛愛□
□Love love love say love love□
□現在來點男高音□
□Now give me some tenor□
□現在給我一些愛□
□Now give me some love love love love□
□會讓你受傷□
□Gonna get you down down down□
□我要嘗一嘗棒棒糖□
□I gonna try aboutlolly, lolly, lollipop□
□用力吸，用力吸，用力吸□
□Sucking, sucking, sucking□
□不然愛會讓你受傷□
□Or love's gonna get you down□
好了
All right!
哦，天啊，哦，天啊，哦，天啊！
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
克洛伊，不要自責啦
- Chloe, don't blame yourself. - Oh, my God!
你一直都是小心翼翼的，這次懲罰夠了
You're a ginger. That's punishment enough.
這不是你的錯，不是我們的錯
This is not all your fault. This is on all of us.
如果我們贏不了，那我們是什麼？
So, if we don't win the Worlds, then what are we?
一群出來閒逛的女孩？
Just a bunch of girls that hang out?
那又怎麼樣？
What's wrong with that?
如果我們贏不了，那貝拉樂團就完蛋了
If we don't win, the Bellas are over.
這是我們有史以來面臨的最大的挑戰
This is the biggest challenge that any of us have ever faced.
我九歲的時候，我哥哥想拿我去換一隻小雞，所以
When I was nine years old, my brother tried to sell me for a chicken, so...
如果我能夠讓貝拉樂團回到頂峰，我誰都做
Well, I will do whoever it takes in order for us to get back to the top.
你是指需要做什麼是吧
You mean "whatever" it takes.
當然，我也會這樣做
Yeah, I'll do that, too.
這真是太好了
That's great news. Yes.
我可以下週一過去，我......我太興奮了
No, I can start Monday. I would be stoked to start on...
抱歉，我不是說興奮
Sorry, I don't say "stoked." I don't say stuff like that.
我很好，我很好，你會喜歡我的
I'm, like, I'm pretty cool. You're gonna like me.
好吧，這聽起來也不怎麼好
That was bad, too.
我們要迎頭解決這個問題
We need to attack this problem head-on.
我需要你們百分百集中激光般的注意力，好嗎？
I want 100% commitment and laser focus, right?
太好了，那週一見
Great! I will see you Monday.
貝卡要掛咯
Beca out!
餘熱錄音室
-貝卡 -來了
- Beca. - Yeah.
嘿，女士們，有興趣參加派對嗎？
Hey, ladies. Wanna come to a party?
提基派對哦！這是最好的派對
It's a tiki party. You guys don't even have to wear shoes.
你甚至不用穿鞋子喲
It's the best kind of party.
- 給你. - 嗯
- Here you go. - Sure.
嘿，不錯的表演啊，麻煩鬼，那可是超級帥啊！
Hey, great job, Trebles. You guys killed it.
謝謝
Oh, thank you.
-你也喜歡阿卡貝拉？ -噢，是的
- You like a cappella? - Oh, yeah.
我全心全意想成為貝拉樂團的一員呢
I've got my heart set on being a Bella.
這是我最大的夢想
It's actually at the very top of all my dream boards.
你剛才提到了夢想？
Did I hear mention of dreams?
嗨，我是本傑明，為你服務
Hi. Benjamin Applebaum at your service. Hello.
我必須要說，你真是太富有活力了
I just have to say, you are so spirited. I...
我真的想把你放進盒子裡，然後鋸成兩段
I just wanna put you in a box and saw you in half.
他說的是魔術
For magic.
一種小把戲，他會變魔術
As a part of a trick. He does magic.
－好的 －如果你不理解的話會變得很奇怪
- Right. - It's only weird if you don't embrace it.
夥計，什麼請況？
Dude, explain yourself.
老實說，我都快暈過去了，我該怎麼辦？
I'll be honest, I completely blacked out. How'd I do, man?
說實話我見過你更糟的時候呢
Honestly? I've seen you do worse.
太好了
Awesome.
這都過去好幾個月了，我們還收到恐嚇信？
It's been months and we're still getting hate mail?
真糟糕
Sucks!
「致你們的糟糕處境「
"For your hairy situation"?
噢
Oh.
好了，我們已經正式註冊了!
Okay, we are officially registered.
女士們，準備好你們的護照，因為我要即將要去到
Update your passports, ladies, because we are going
陽光充足的並且美不勝收的哥本哈根
to the very sunny, very beautiful, Copenhagen!
- 耶，太好了- 對的!
- Yeah! Nice! - Yes!
噢
Oh.
哥本哈根在哪裡？
Where is that?
我不知道，我對地圖一竅不通
I don't know. I failed Maps.
看起來這場比賽已經被那個愚蠢的德國樂隊控制了
It looks like the competition has been dominated
他們取代了我們的巡演
by that stupid German group that took over our tour.
是他們偷走了我們的巡演
- You mean "stole" our tour. - Word.
我們要探查一下他們這群混蛋的實力
We need to scout those Deutsche-bags.
沒錯
Yes.
他們能有多強呢？
But how good can they be?
在大衛哈塞爾霍夫之後就沒有出過好歌手了
Germany hasn't produced a good singer since David Hasselhoff.
我們將要打敗他們
We're gonna crush them.
然後我們就可以
And when we do,
理直氣壯的面對這些發恐嚇信的笨蛋，例如
we can stick it to these chumps who send us all this hate mail, like,
桑尼亞索托馬約爾
"Sonia Sotomayor."
去死吧
婊子們
這個有偏見的婊子
Judgy bitch.
貝拉樂團回歸啦
The Bellas are back!
- 耶！- 耶！我們回來了
- Yeah! Whoo-hoo! - Yeah! We're back.
今天有人見到貝卡了麼？
Has anyone talked to Beca today?
所以?
So?
第一天上班緊張嗎？
Any first-day jitters?
餘熱錄音室
不不，我要變得疏離而情緒化
No, no. You know, I'm just gonna
那些藝術家喜歡這樣的
be moody and distant. Artists love that.
我知道我喜歡這樣的
I know I love that.
來，去吧
Here you go.
好的
Okay.
夥計，為什麼我覺得有點內疚？
Dude, why do I feel so guilty?
我為貝拉樂團付出了那麼多，不是嗎？
I've given a lot to the Bellas, right?
整整三年
It's, like, three years of my life.
沒錯，貝卡，你不該為自己的任何嘗試感到內疚
Yeah, Bec, you should not feel guilty at all about taking your shot.
這是一件非常中要的事對嗎？
This is a big deal, right?
是的，這是一件重要的事
- Yes, it's a very big deal. - Okay.
－去吧 －好的
- Go. - All right.
沒有什麼事能阻止我的女人
Nothing's gonna stop my girl!
餘熱錄音室
我不認識他
I don't know him!
貝卡要震驚世界喲！
Becs in effects, y'all!
你可以走了
You can go!
準備好了還是？
Are you ready, or...
BGM：《Change Your Life》- Iggy Azalea & T.I.（專輯：The New Classic）2013
好了，大伙們，過來一下
Okay, everybody, huddle up.
快點快點，麻煩快點到桌子那邊去，起來，快點
Let's go, let's go, let's go! Get up!
麻煩快點到桌子那邊去，起來，快點
Come on! To the table, please! To the table!
最後到的要幫弗蘭克在油管
Last one at this table has to help Frank watch YouTube videos
找到下一個賈斯丁比伯
to find the next Justin Bieber.
嘿，我下周就25歲了
Hey, so, I'm turning 25 next week,
有人想喝點酒慶祝一下嗎？
if anybody wants to get some drinks, celebrate.
弗蘭克，夥計，安靜點
Frank, buddy, less talk.
非常感謝大家
Thank you so much.
好了，請看屏幕
Okay, my people, check it out.
這個...
That...
這是...達克斯，叫上技術員，你有打電話給技術員嗎？
This... Dax, the tech guy. Did you call the tech guy?
有的，我打給他了
Yeah, I talked to him.
我的人生一帆風順，你懂嗎？
Do you understand that everything else in my life works?
嗯
Uh-huh.
所以今天這裡也不能有什麼問題
So, I just need everything here to work, too, okay?
－他說他會回我電話的 －哦， 天啊
- Well, he said he was gonna call me back. - Oh, my God.
要我現在打電話給他嗎？
You want me to call him now?
不要現在打
Don't do it now.
好吧
Okay.
我們開始吧
There we go.
這是萊昂本尊
That is the Lion himself.
這個是傳奇歌手史努比道格
That is the legendary Snoop D-O-Double-G
他在莫斯科的一次聖誕樹點燈儀式上獻唱《白色聖誕》
singing White Christmas at a tree-lighting ceremony in Moscow.
他的音樂凝聚在一起的力量深深感動了
And he was so moved by the power of music
整個世界
to unite the world or some shit,
於是他想要發行他的個人聖誕專輯
that now he wants to drop his own cool Christmas album.
因為我多次獲得格萊美獎
And because I sleep on a bed of Grammys,
所以他雇我作為他的製作人
he has decided to hire me to produce it. Now...
但是史努比道格已經發行過升段專輯了
But Snoop Dogg already dropped a Christmas album.
如果你好像我一樣聽過那張專輯
If you had listened to the album like I did,
和歌手T.I.坐在一架金色的滑翔機，在天上翱翔
stranded in the air with T.I. on a golden hang glider,
你就會知道，這張專輯沒有一首歌是能成為經典的
then you would have known that none of the songs were the classics.
聽這張專輯，我不得不到兩個不同的場合
I've had to listen to that album on two separate occasions.
和T.I.翱翔
Hang glider with T. I.
和坐在艾米納米建造的火箭裡面
And also a rocket ship that Eminem has built.
這張專輯不會大賣
It doesn't go anywhere,
但是他懷著夢想，好嗎？
but he's got dreams for it, okay?
現在，我需要你閉嘴
So I need you to close your mouth.
這就是問題所在，大伙
Herein lies the problem, everybody.
昨天我查了一下，聖誕主題的專輯超過一百萬張
Last time I checked, there are over a million Christmas albums
裡面有超過十首都他媽是一模一樣的
with the same 10 damn songs on them.
所以夥計們，我告訴你們
So, guys, I'm telling you, man,
我現在需要大家馬上準備好
I need all hands on deck right now
想想如何讓這張專輯格外出眾
to come up with ideas on how to make this one stand out.
好嗎？你們懂了嗎？
Okay? You got it?
準備好就說，我需要你們的主意
Fire when ready. I want to hear ideas.
什麼都行
Anything.
有人有主意嗎？
Anybody.
有主意就說出來
Anybody right now would be great.
- 有人想告訴我他的主意嗎？- 如果我們弄一些狗...
- Anybody to talk... - What if we got those dogs...
任何人除了你
Anybody but you.
如果我們找一些狗在背景唱《玲兒響叮噹》？
What if we got those dogs that bark Jingle Bells to back him up?
讓我猜猜
And let me, let me, let me guess, let me guess.
你想讓狗來伴唱是因為他的名字叫史努比」狗「？
You want those dogs to back him up because he's "Snoop Dogg"?
沒錯
Yeah!
這真是一個好主意...
That is a really great example
才怪呢！
of a horrible idea.
跑一圈
Take a lap.
- 什麼？ -跑一圈
- What? - Take a lap.
但是我穿著緊身牛仔褲
But I'm wearing skinny jeans.
我不管
I don't care.
快跑
Go. Go.
跑起來，我要看到你抬起膝蓋來
Let's go. I wanna see knees up.
請抬起膝蓋來
Knees up, please.
夥計們，我應該給多你們一點時間
Guys, I should give you a little more time.
一分鐘，你們有一分鐘時間，六十秒
A minute. You got one minute. 60 seconds.
我的時間就像一個帶著寶石的幼兒，珍貴且短
My time is like a toddler in a tiara, okay? Precious and short.
我需要非常好的主意，史努比就要到了
I need really great ideas. Snoop is coming!
噢，抱歉，我的胸快炸了，我剛才一直在跳
Oh. Sorry, my boobs are all crazy. I was just jumping.
我剛剛從試音選拔那裡過來，你們不在那裡
I just came from auditions. You guys weren't there.
我希望能唱給你們聽聽
I was hoping for the chance to sing for you.
哦，抱歉，幫不了你，我們不允許在招新了
No, can't help you. We're not allowed to take anyone else new.
哦，不，等等
Oh, no, no, no. Wait, wait, wait!
我是榮格家的
I'm a Junk!
榮格家又怎麼了？
What'd you say about your junk?
我是艾米麗榮格
I'm Emily Junk.
我知道這來有點奇怪，榮格是我媽的姓
I know, it's weird. It's my mom's last name.
我爸姓哈登，所以...
My dad's last name is Hardon, so...
嗯...
Um...
我是老成員的後代
I'm a Legacy.
榮格，榮格
Junk. Junk.
我媽媽是貝拉樂團的成員
My mom was a Bella.
你媽媽是凱瑟琳榮格？
Your mother is Katherine Junk?
誰？
Who?
1981年最佳阿卡貝拉歌手
Only the top bitch of the 1981 Bellas.
她開創了分音時的甩臀動作
She pioneered the syncopated booty shake.
而且她的聲音可以穿越五個八度
And word is she has a five-octave vocal range.
沒錯，她現在也是一樣
Yep, still does.
你不會想聽見她對我爸飆高音的
You do not want to hear that woman doing it with my dad. Whew.
這麼說很奇怪耶
What an odd thing to say.
沒錯
True.
如果一個後代想要試一試，我們一定要允許她試
If a Legacy wants to audition, we have to let her.
好的，嗯...
Okay, um...
讓我們看看你的本事
Show us what you got.
現在？在這裡？在這裡？現在？
Right now? Right here? Right here, right now.
沒問題
Yeah.
好的，我想演唱一首我現在正在寫的歌
Okay, um, I'd like to perform an original song that I've been working on.
因為儘管我還沒有寫完，所以
I'm not quite finished with it though,
所以不要把它說的太差好嗎
so let's not be dicks about it.
抱歉，這聽起來很粗俗是嗎？
Sorry, that was crass, wasn't it?
胖艾米，你的「逼」很可愛
Fat Amy, you have a lovely vagina.
謝謝，開始吧
Thank you. Proceed.
□當明天來臨時□
□ When tomorrow comes □
□我將一己之力□
□I will be on my own□
□害怕的感覺不斷湧來□
□Feeling frightened up□
□我不知道會發生什麼事□
□The things that I don't konw□
□當明天來臨時□
□When tomorrow comes□
□明天來臨時□
□雖然道路漫長□
□And though the road is long□
□我抬頭看向天空□
□I look up to the sky□
□一切回首□
□Turn the so around□
這一段我還在修改，所以...
No. That one, I'm not... I'm still kind of tinkering with that verse.
這首歌還沒有完全寫好
So it's not... Nothing's really completely set.
□當我有了你，我就像擁有一切□
□I got all I need when I got you and I□
□我環顧四周 而我看見了美滿的生活□
□I look around me, and see sweet life□
□我被困在黑暗中 但你是我的照明燈 □
□I'm stuck in the dark but you're my flashlight □
□你抓著我 將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□Getting me, getting me though the night□
□你是我的照明燈□
□You are my flashlight□
請等我們一分鐘好嗎？
Would you excuse us for just one second?
她非常不錯耶，我們可以招她嗎？
She's pretty good. Can't we take her?
等等，你想我們說什麼？她就站在那裡
What do you expect us to say? She's standing right there.
－她肯定不能獨唱 －沒錯
- She's definitely not a soloist. - No.
嚴格來說，是她找上門來的，所以我們沒有違反任何規定
Technically, she came to us, so really we're not breaking any rules.
嗯，這的確是一個很好的漏洞
Yeah, it's the perfect loophole.
有新人總是一件好事
You know, it's always good to have an extra body.
以防萬一我們有人被綁架
Just in case one of us gets kidnapped for ransom,
被扔進游輪上的集裝箱
is thrown into a shipping container,
強迫吃樹葉和加油單據
and is made to eat only leaves and gas receipts.
嗯，我同意，我們需要注入新血液
Mmm, I agree. We need new blood.
我覺得我們不應該在貝卡不在的時候做決定
I don't think we should decide anything without Beca.
我保留意見
I keep a penny under my tongue.
你們不覺得她從不睜開眼睛
Did anyone else think it was creepy
有點嚇人嗎？
that she never really opened her eyes the whole time?
再說一遍，我們正在討論她
Again, we're talking about her
- 而她就站在那裡 - 噢，是的
- and she's standing right there. - Oh, yeah.
但是如果說她的缺點，首先是她像長頸鹿一樣的腿
But if we're gonna talk negatives, let's start with the giraffe legs.
好吧，我們來投票吧
Okay, let's take a vote on it.
同意她加入的，唱升G調
Anyone who wants her in, sing a G-sharp.
否則，唱降E調
Anyone who doesn't, sing an E-flat.
- 好的 -一、二.....
- Okay. - One, two...
我喜歡你的襯衫
I like your shirt.
歡迎加入貝拉樂團
Welcome to the Bellas!
我的天！哇！
O-M-a-ca-G! Whoo!
- 哦，停下來，別轉了，停下來 - 耶，停下來，停下
- Oh. Stop, girl, stop. - Yeah, stop, stop it.
- 孩子，停下 - 抱歉
- Girl, stop. - Sorry.
什麼時候開入會儀式呢？
So, when does initiation start?
你們往我頭上套黑罩的時候我會假裝很吃驚的樣子
Tell you what, I'll go back to my dorm and pretend to be surprised
然後讓我把魔方擰好
when you throw the hood over my head and make me solve a Rubik's Cube
從衛生棉裡吸伏特加
while sucking vodka from a maxi pad.
我媽媽告訴我入會儀式是這樣的
That's what my mom said happened.
嗯，不能這樣做
Mmm, no can do.
你看看周圍
Well, look around.
我們已經沒有衛生棉可用了，所以......
We don't exactly have a maxi pad to spare, so...
好了，女士們，拿出你們的勇氣，派對時間到了
All right, grab your guts, ladies! It's party time!
我們拿到了去哥本哈根的機票，有了一個全新的貝拉樂團
We've got tickets to Copenhagen and a brand new Bella!
- 出發咯- 好吧
- Let's go! - All right.
- 我應該... - 來吧，女孩！
- Should I... - Come on, girl!
算了，我還是把我的包留在這裡吧
I'm gonna just leave my bag here.
讓我們去找點茬
Let's go get into treble!
這個灌木叢一直在這裡嗎？
Has this bush always been here?
噢！看看這個！
Oh! Watch this.
你知道那裡有一扇門，是嗎？
You know there's a gate, right?
哇
Wow.
這是我第一次參加大學的派對
My first college party.
對，但這不只是一個大學派對
Yeah, well, this isn't just any college party.
只有阿卡貝拉的成員才可以參加，耶！
This is a cappella only! Yeah.
所以說，做好準備，待會你會見到一群慾求不滿的男人
So, get prepared to meet a lot of sexually confused men.
貝拉們，歡迎，歡迎，歡迎！
Bellas! Welcome, welcome, welcome!
傑西，貝卡呢？ 我以為她和你在一起？
Jesse! Where is Beca? I thought she was gonna be with you tonight.
我以為她和你在一起
I thought she was with you.
嘿，你叫本傑，對嗎？
Hey! Benji, right?
這些... 這些根本不是單詞...
Those aren't... Okay, those aren't words.
你在說什麼？
I'm sorry?
... ...電影？
...the movies?
你是在約我嗎？
Are you asking me out?
- 是的 - 真的？
- Yes. - Yeah?
噢，真是太貼心了
Oh. That's so sweet.
只是...這是我在大學的第一天，所以...
It's just, my... It's my first day. Um...
我不想太著急，想慢慢來
I wasn't really planning on rushing in on anything.
BGM：《Fist Pump, Jump Jump》- Ying Yang Twins & Greg Tecoz (單曲專輯：Fist Pump, Jump Jump) 2012
- 嘿，噢！- 嘿，你來了！
- Hey! Oh. - Hey! You made it!
對，不能錯過這個我們最後一個風帽派對
Yeah, I couldn't miss our last Hood Night party.
- 噢 - 所以？
- Oh. - So?
你的實習怎麼樣？
How was the internship?
讓我大開眼界，說實話，他們他們不會亂搞一通
Eye-opening. Yeah, they do not mess around.
嘿，克洛伊問你在哪裡
Hey, Chloe asked where you were.
什麼你沒有告訴她？
Why didn't you tell her?
哦，她只是...
Oh. She's just...
她現在心裡全都是世界大賽，我準備遲點再告訴她
She's locked into the Worlds right now and I'm looking for the right time.
我會告訴她的
I'll tell her.
邦博回來了
Bumper's back!
哇呼！
Whoo!
我回來當保安來了
Campus security!
邦博，邦博
Bumper! Bumper!
胖艾米也回來了
Fat Amy's back!
因為我從未離去，因為我還在這裡
'Cause I never left 'cause I'm still here.
但是我回來了，所以說這是件大事，因為我回來了
Whoo! But I'm back, so it's a big deal because I've arrived again!
相對於那些離校多年的人
You know, for someone who left school years ago,
你的單聲道更難顫動
you're harder to shake than mono.
我有一條非常爆炸的新聞
I've got some pretty big news.
什麼新聞？
What?
我被推薦成一名知名的電視唱歌比賽的
I have been hand-plucked to be put on a waiting list
正式比賽候選人
to be put on a very well-known TV singing competition.
- 真的? - 沒錯
- Really? - Yep.
我知道你在想什麼
I know what you're thinking.
"哦，邦博
"Oh, Bumper.
閉嘴然後來親我，邦博「
"You shut your face and kiss me, Bumper."
不
No.
-「求你了，邦博」 -閉嘴...
"Bumper, please, just shut your trap."
我不是這樣說話的
That is not how I talk.
－你就是這樣講話的 －我不是
- You talk exactly like this. - Do not.
是的，你是這樣說話的
Yes, you do.
不是
I don't.
－你閉嘴吧 －你才閉嘴
- So shut up. - You shut up.
嗨!
Hi!
嗨
Hi.
有幸見到一手成立貝拉樂團的人
I am so excited to meet the woman
我真是太激動了
who single-handedly created the Bella sound.
我們成為姐妹了
We're sisters!
我真不能相信我們成為姐妹了
I can't believe we're sisters!
- 噢，對的，嗨! - 嗨!
- Oh! Yeah, hi! - Hi!
克洛伊發短信告訴我說我們有了一個新成員
Chloe texted me we added a Legacy.
我根本不知道有這樣一件事
I didn't even know that was a thing.
噓
Shh.
再強調一次我們為什麼來車展？
Remind me again why we are at a car show.
我們來這裡只有一個目的
We're here for one reason and one reason only.
我們是來偵查我們的對手的
To scout the competition.
知己知彼，百戰百勝
It's totally gonna help us win the Worlds if we know what we're up against.
好了
All right.
那些偷走我們巡演的小偷在哪裡？
Now, where are those tour thieves?
史黛西
Stacie!
不要太露骨了
Keep it in your pants, maybe.
－史黛西 －怎麼了？
- Stacie! - What?
什麼鬼...
What the...
這一切本來是屬於我們的
This all should have been ours!
我討厭這些德國人
I hate these Germans.
天啊 !
Holy a-ca-mole!
好的，這些車子移開了，目前還沒有發生任何事
Okay, the cars moved. Nothing else happened yet.
但是它們是無人駕駛的移開了
But they're moving backwards. With ghosts driving them.
我們是達斯發聲機
We are Das Sound Machine.
一個來自德國的樂團，通過巡演為你們營造聽覺盛宴
A German collective, operating in concert to create sonic mastery.
還有什麼更好的方式來欣賞汽車之美呢？
What better way to appreciate automotive perfection?
□他們無法控制我們□
□They will not control us□
□我們將會是勝利者□
□We will be victorious□
□這些妄想狂正在巔峰□
□Paranoia is in bloom the PR□
《Uprising》- Muse（專輯：The Resistance）2009
□這些遺傳會繼續下去□
□Transmissions will resume They'll try to□
□他們將會試著下藥麻痺讓我們所有人保持沉默並且如此希望□
□ Push drugs keep us all dumbed down and hope that□
□而我們將永遠看不見圍繞在身邊的真相□
□We will never see the truth around□
□所以說，來吧□
□So come on!□
□其他的承諾,其他的景象,那些其他□
□Another promise, another scene, another□
□一個包裝好的包裹無法設計我們陷入貪慾之中□
□A package not to keep us trapped in greed□
□那些用綠色的皮帶包裹我們所有的心智□
□With all the green belts wrapped around our minds and endless□
□而無窮無境的終點線讓真實被永遠限制住□
□red tape to keep the truth confined□
天啊，他們好協調
Man, they massive!
我們要怎樣和這樣強大的隊伍比拚啊
How are we gonna compete with a group that size?
他們簡直是神同步
They're so freakin' in sync.
□他們不能強迫我們□
□They will not force us□
□他們將會停止使我們墮落□
□They will stop degrading□
□而我們會獲勝□
□We will be victorious□
□前進□
□Come on□
我們鼓掌嗎?
Do we clap?
我們鼓掌嗎? Do we clap我們鼓掌嗎?
Do we clap? Do we clap?
禮儀上鼓兩下吧
Politely clap.
巴頓貝拉，你們來看我們表演？
Barden Bellas. You came here to see us?
因為你們是...你們美國孩子們說的「廢物」？
Is it because you are... What do the American kids say, "Jelly"?
我們才不是「廢物」呢
We are so not "jelly."
我們非常感謝你們幫我們把這個巡演變為現實
We should really thank you for making this tour a reality,
還有你們裝模作樣的蠢樣
you know, with your bumbling ineptitude.
我們應該給她們送點東西，果籃怎麼樣
We should send them something. Fruit basket?
嗯，嗯
Yum, yum.
或者送些迷你小鬆餅？
Or would you prefer mini-muffins?
好了，我們不是過來吵架的
Okay, we didn't come here to start something with you guys.
我們只是要在世界大賽之前考察一下你們
We just wanted to check you out before the Worlds,
然後再把你們打得屁滾尿流
where we're gonna kick your ass.
- 什麼？ - 沒錯
- What? - That's right.
就憑你們？
You?
讓我們屁滾尿流？
You are the kicker of ass?
沒錯
Yeah.
你的身軀真是袖珍啊
You are so tiny.
像一個小精靈一樣
Like an elf.
或者像仙女？小妖怪？
Or is it a fairy? Sprite?
「食人巨怪」
"Troll."
就是這個，像食人巨怪
That's it. You are like a troll.
你
You
身材完美
are physically flawless.
謝謝
Thank you.
但這不代表我喜歡你
But it doesn't mean I like you.
我們不擔心世界大賽是因為
We are not scared about the Worlds,
貝拉樂團在舞台上時，會所有人眼前一亮的
because when the Bellas hit the stage, we are gonna blow minds.
用什麼讓觀眾眼前一亮？
With what?
用鬆弛艾比的寶寶陰溝？
More of Flabby Abby's baby chute?
那不是我的名字
That's not my name.
我不知道你的名字
I don't know your name.
可能是任何稱呼
Could be anything.
超重丹尼斯，遲鈍蒂娜，懶惰蘇珊
Obese Denise, Inflexible Tina, Lazy Susan.
我的名字叫胖艾米，我中午吃像你這樣的德國酸泡菜
Mein name ist Fat Amy, und I eat krauts like you for lunch.
你的對員...就像你們說的...一團糟
Your team is like a... How do you say that? A heated mess.
你懂的，在混亂中加點熱
You know, a mess where heat is applied to it,
只是以前是有一點混亂，現在更混亂了而已
so what once was a little messy is now even messier.
親們，請接受我的建議
Darlings, please take my advice.
不要嘗試打敗我們
Don't try to beat us.
你們做不到的
You can't.
因為我們是最棒的
We're the best.
現在我要去鬆鬆我的脖子了
And now I really must go rest my neck.
低著頭看你們，脖子都酸了
It is sore from looking down on you.
好了
Okay,
你們讓我非常慾求不滿
just because you're making me very sexually confused,
但是這不代表我們就怕你們了
does not mean that you are intimidating.
我們沒有什麼可輸的
We have nothing to lose.
- 我們一無所有 - 好了
- We have literally nothing! - Okay.
再見，賤人！
A-ca wiedersehen, bitches!
噢，我怎麼了，手勢太多了
Oh, what is happening? I am using my hands so much.
好了，女士們，集中注意力
All right, ladies, focus up.
我們需要打敗這些德國垃圾
We need to beat those German dummkopfs.
- 是的 - 沒錯
- Yes! - Yeah.
好的，我們在達斯發聲機自己開啟的遊戲中打敗他們
Okay, we're gonna beat DSM at their own game.
做和他們一樣的表演，但是做的更好一些
Do what they do, just better.
我們要做全部的技能評測
And we're about to do a full skills assessment
和設計比賽的舞蹈
to blow out our choreography to match.
但是最重要的是我們要開心，對嗎？
But the important thing is that we have fun, right?
後代，別誤會了
Uh, Legacy, don't take this the wrong way,
其實你是這裡最笨的
but you're the dumbest person alive.
BGM：《A Different Beat》- Little Mix（專輯： Salute）2013
你是一隻貓
And you're a cat!
一...
And one...
好了，莉莉，你真的把我嚇到了
Okay, Lilly, that's really scaring me.
這看起來很奇怪
That just looks weird.
人類不是小鳥
People are not birds.
側翻身，然後轉圈
Cartwheel. And roll! Amy, that wasn't a roll.
再來一次
Again.
我們今天沒有練習唱歌，這不是很奇怪嗎？
Is it weird that we never got around to singing today?
沒有編曲我們很難開始聯繫
Uh, well, it's kind of hard to start singing
這都怪我
without arrangements, and that's on me.
謝謝你提醒我
So thank you for reminding me.
沒事，貝卡，我們需要編曲，越快越好
Yeah, Bec, we're gonna need that ASAP
這樣我們就可以開始編舞了
so we can start nailing down our choreography.
- 這是任務之首，克洛伊 - 棒極了!
- Right on top of that, Chlo. - Awes!
對，好極了
Yeah, awes.
其實我一直想告訴你們
So I just wanted to let you know that I've been working really hard
我一直在努力冷靜下來，張大眼睛
on, you know, calming my nerves and keeping my eyes open.
我經常在想你是否能給我一些幫助
I was wondering if you could give me some pointers, maybe.
你懂的，在唱歌方面...
And, you know, with the singing...
我不知道你會安排我唱哪個部分
I don't know exactly where you're gonna put me in the songs, but I...
沒有冒犯的意思，但我現在要離開一下
I don't mean to be rude. I just have somewhere that I need to be.
嗯...
Um...
你今天做的很好
You did great today.
謝謝
Thanks.
□雪橇鈴兒響□
□Sleigh bells ring□
《Winter Wonderland》- 聖誕節歌曲
□你在聽嗎□
□Are you listening□
□小路上□
□In the lane□
□積雪在閃光□
□Snow is glistening□
□美景當前□
□A beautiful sight□
□今晚我們很開心□
□We're happy tonight□
□當走在冬日的仙境裡□
□Walking in a winter wonderland□
等等，等我一下
Wait, hold up. Just hold up for a second.
等等，等什麼？
"Wait, hold up"?
我現在聽起來挺不錯，你在說什麼
Man, I sound awesome right now. What are you talking about?
不是你的問題，技術問題，休息幾分鐘
Nah! It's not you, it's a tech thing. So just you go ahead and take five.
最好是技術問題
It better be a tech thing,
因為我現在聽到的聲音可是完美無缺的
'cause the way I sound in my eardrums, this is immaculate, man.
這首歌沒有任何特別的地方，一點都沒有
This song, there's nothing, nothing special about it yet.
你懂我的意思嘛？
Do you know what I mean?
有什麼點子嗎？因為我...
Any ideas? Because I...
好吧，聽我說
All right, um, hear me out.
拜託，達克斯，拜託
Please, Dax. Please...
我們可以去除那些鈴鐺
We could remove the sleigh bells
然後把克林巴琴加進去
and put in kalimba.
你知道的，那種用拇指彈的琴
You know, the finger thing.
我知道什麼是克林巴琴是什麼，我知道它怎麼彈，好嗎
I know what a kalimba does. I know how it's operated, okay?
- 克林巴琴...- 別再說了
- Kalimba... - Don't say it again.
去角落蹲著，拿著你的午餐去角落吃
Go in the corner. Go eat your lunch in the corner.
那我的斯里拉查怎麼辦
But what am I gonna do with my sriracha?
你再說一句話
Say one more hipster thing,
我就把你塞進老式，裝低音管的箱子裡去
and I'm gonna shove you in your vintage bassoon case.
明白嗎？
Okay?
轉過去
Turn.
要高標準，明白嗎？
Aim higher, people. Okay?
專注你們的表現
And be very careful what you pitch to me next.
然他用同樣的方法在唱一邊
Um, just have him sing it again, the same way.
你是誰？
Who are you?
小人物，只是一個小人物，我有一個點子
Nobody. Literally nobody. I just had a thought.
別這樣，好吧，好吧
No, okay, okay.
當然
Sure.
其他人沒有想法
Nobody else has an idea.
讓我們，嗯，跟剛才那樣
Let's, uh, do it exactly the same way.
再來一遍
Again.
好的，侄子
Will do, nephew.
□聖誕老人來了□
□Here comes Santa Claus□
《Here Comes Santa Claus》- 聖誕節兒歌
□聖誕老人來了□
□Here comes Santa Claus□
□就沿著聖誕老人的小路□
□Right down Santa Claus Lane□
□Vixen和Blitzen以及他所有的馴鹿□
□Vixen Blitzen all his reindeer□
□都賣力的拉著韁繩□
□Pulling on the reins□
或者可以做一些不一樣的
Or it can be something different. It can...
好吧
Okay.
這真是太棒了，史努比
That was amazing, Snoop.
非常謝謝你
Thank you so very much.
兄弟，你可以休息一下了
You can take a small break, man.
全部都很完美，很專業
Everything, perfection. Perfection.
就像看汽車電影一樣美妙
Groovy like a drive-in movie.
你會唱歌
You can sing.
是的，我曾經獲得過三次全美阿卡貝拉比賽冠軍
Um, yeah, I'm a three-time collegiate a cappella champion, so...
我們都在各自領域獲得了巨大的成功
We're both huge successes in our fields.
是的
Yeah.
是的，沒錯
Yeah, let's say that.
嗯，那你在這裡做什麼事
Uh, what do you do here?
煮咖啡，買墨西哥卷之類的
I just get coffee and burritos and stuff.
我想創作音樂
I wanna produce music.
達克斯，幫我個忙好嗎
Dax? Can you do me a favor?
轉過身來，看看這段對話
Turn around right now, and watch this exchange.
這才是「有價值」的對話
That's "value added." Okay?
如果你有想要給我聽的樣片，我會抽出時間來聽的
If you have any demos you'd like me to listen to, I'll make the time.
噢，真的？
Oh, seriously?
- 嗯，真的 - 噢！
- Mmm-hmm. Seriously, yeah. - Oh!
達克斯，你看到這裡發生什麼事了麼
Dax, did you see what happened there?
- 嗯嗯 - 她做了一些很有幫助的事
- Uh-huh. - She did something that was helpful.
現在我將聽她的樣片以作為獎勵
And now I'm going to reward her by listening to her demos.
轉回去
Turn back around.
現在！請轉回去
Now! Turn around, please.
所以，史努比，我們有個主意
So, Snoop, uh, buddy, we've got an idea.
我也有
Me, too.
在地上用水上滑板
Water skis, but for dry land.
很逼真的表演，你懂我的意思嗎
Real playa. You know what I'm talking about?
很棒的想法
Brilliant.
那是一定的
Fo shizzle, dizzle.
我會記下來的
I'll write that down.
好的，拜託你了
Yeah, please.
BGM：《Trumpets》- Jason DeRulo（專輯： Tattoos）2013
你們在幹什麼
What am I looking at?
我們在玩枕頭大戰
We're pillow fighting!
啊哈！
Aah!
你知道這讓女性的步伐倒退了大概三十年嗎
You know this sets women back, like, 30 years?
我們只是放鬆一下
We're just relieving some stress.
在這個走廊上
This was on the porch.
噢！！
Ooh.
這是什麼？看起來好高級的樣子
What is that? Looks fancy.
我們收到要求，去某個派對唱歌
Looks like we've been invited to sing at some kind of a party.
我們要去唱歌？
We're going to sing?
終於等到這一天了
Finally!
這好像是地址和通行口令
Well, there's just an address and a password.
- 這是多麼性感神秘 - 沒錯！
- How sexy and mysterious. - Yeah.
就像我的牙，都是別人的舊牙
Like how all my teeth are from other people.
呀！
Ow!
還有其他害怕的人嗎？
Anyone else scared?
沒有了，我已經活得比我預計的要長了
Not really. I already lived longer than I expected.
口令
Password.
屁聲
Fart noise.
你沒有看到那個括號嗎？
Did you not see the parentheses?
貝拉樂團，很高興你們來了，請進
Bellas! I'm so glad you all came. Come on in.
女士們，站在你們面前的正是
Standing in front of you, ladies,
全世界最瘋狂的阿卡貝拉粉絲
happens to be the world's biggest a cappella fan.
我們遇見你了！
We found you!
你好，我在這裡
Hello. Here I am.
我們能為你做什麼呢？
What can we do for you?
上周我在撒尿的時候，突然想到
So, last week when I was having a tinkle, it occurred to me...
別，別
Do not, do not!
抱歉
Sorry.
這真是粗魯
That was rude.
你們不能到一個紳士家裡，然後摸摸他的鵝
You do not come to a gentleman's house and touch his goose.
所以我們是到早了，還是...
So are we early, or...
事實上，你們來遲了
Actually, you're pretty late. Come on, let's go!
今晚精彩紛呈
This is the big time.
兩點鐘的方向是達斯發聲機
Das Sound Machine, two o'clock.
小老鼠，我們又見面了
Tiny Mouse! We meet again.
又要得到一次口頭的勝利了
Another verbal beatdown.
點亮了我的一天
Highlight of my day.
所以說你們是放棄了那個在世界大賽打敗我們的愚蠢計劃了嗎
So, have you abandoned your foolish plans to face us at the Worlds?
想的美，花瓶
You wish, you gorgeous specimen.
她真討我喜歡
She's really in my head.
非常好
Very well.
我很高興把你們送到那裡去
I'll be happy to send you there.
把你們寄過去
I'll mail you.
大封的郵件也貴不到那你去哪裡去
Large envelope costs nothing.
但是總是貴了那麼一點
Well, it will cost more than nothing.
但是總比海運一匹馬便宜
But still cheaper than shipping, like, a horse, or perhaps an adult moose.
你沒有想過你也許太大了
Did you ever think maybe you're too big?
- 郵寄你要花費一大筆錢 - 淡定點
- It would cost a fortune to mail you. - Easy.
你巨大無比
You're enormous!
好吧
Okay.
也許我們應該叫她「活波老鼠」
I think we should change her name to "Feisty Mouse."
沒錯
Yeah.
只要我們找到一雙更高的高跟鞋
Just need to find, like, a taller pair of shoes.
-這不是什麼大問題 - 嘿！
- Wasn't a big deal. - Hey!
嘿，你在幹什麼？發生了什麼事？
Hey! What are you doing here? What is going on?
- 歡迎 - 我想我要走了
- Welcome! - I guess I gotta go.
- 不，為什麼 - 我不知道
- No. Why? - I don't know.
歡迎來到全美第一屆阿卡貝拉
Welcome to the first ever showdown
激光忍者龍聯賽
of the National A Cappella Laser Ninja Dragon League!
你們喜歡嗎
Can you dig it?
好吧，接下來介紹我們的比賽隊伍
Okay, let's meet our teams.
你一個出場的是麻煩鬼樂團
First we have The Treblemakers!
耶！
Yeah!
好了，接下來是巴頓貝拉樂團
Okay. We have the Barden Bellas.
然後我們還有音調掛鉤樂團
We have the Tone Hangers!
- 冰糕 - 冰糕
- Sorbet - Sorbet
有個櫻桃在上面
And a cherry on top
然後是在全國巡演中抽空來的
And taking a break from their national tour,
達斯發聲機樂團
Das Sound Machine!
- DSM! - 耶!
- DSM! - Ja!
還有威斯康星州的驕傲，綠灣包裝工隊
And the pride of Wisconsin, the Green Bay Packers!
走吧，開始吧，寶貝
Let's go! Here we go, baby!
- 我們上! - 什麼？
- Let's go! - What?
我想當那個人體三明治中間的胸脯肉
I'd like to be the brisket in that man-sandwich.
好的，接下來我們的做法是這樣的
Well, here's how this is gonna work.
當我指向你的時候，你要唱一首歌
When I point to you, you sing a song
歌曲將會是大屏幕中各種分類中的一種
from one of the categories that's gonna appear up there on the big board.
規則只有一個
There's only one rule.
你們必須合拍，過來一個
You have to meet the beat. Here, come here.
但是你們必須按歌曲「追隨領導者」的風格唱
But you have to do it "Follow the Leader" style.
噢，天啊！
Oh, boy!
噢，我的上帝
Oh, goodness.
這真有趣
That was fun.
現在，鑰匙你跑調了，你們隊就出局了
Now, if you can't carry the tune, the whole team's out.
也就是說，你麼可以走人了
As in, you gone! And then...
科尼利厄斯，這太重了，我不是和你說過了嗎？
Cornelius, this is too heavy. I told you before.
我在對國旗敬禮的時候弄傷了胳膊
Because I hurt my arm saluting the flag.
好吧，對不起
Okay, sorry.
現在，贏者將會獲得
Now, the winners will get
史詩般的吹噓權利
epic bragging rights!
- 什麼 - 就這樣？
- What? - That's it?
噢，抱歉，我是忘記說了什麼嗎
Oh. And I'm sorry. Did I not mention this?
一張價值 42,000 美元的餐飲禮品卡
A $42,000 gift card to Dave and Buster's!
我本來就想去那裡的
I was going there anyway. I was going there anyway.
我知道克萊馬修斯想要這個
I know Clay Matthews wants it.
好的，接下來，我們開始吧
Okay. All right, let's get this thing started.
讓我們看看第一個歌曲分類
Let's take a look at the first category.
關    於    臀    部   的   歌
噢，關於臀部的歌
Ooh. Songs about butts.
好吧
Okay.
- 在廣播都有播過是嗎？- 沒錯
- Anything on the radio, basically, right? - Right.
想想你們要唱什麼
Think about what you're gonna sing.
那我們就從達斯發聲機開始
Let's start with Das Sound Machine!
□她的屁股像卡車一樣大□
□She had dumps like a truck, truck, truck□
□大腿像什麼什麼什麼□
□Thighs like what what what□
□一整晚□
□All night long□
□讓我看看丁字褲□
□Let me see that thong□
□寶貝，那條丁字褲□
□ Baby, that thong, th-th-th-thong□
□搖搖搖□
□Shake, shake, shake□
《Shake Your Booty》- Kc & the Sunshine Band （專輯：Part 3）1976
□擺動你的屁股□
□Shake your booty□
□怎麼樣□
□How□
□搖搖搖□
□Shake, shake, shake□
□擺動你的屁股□
□Shake your booty□
□辣妹牛仔褲包屁屁□
□Shorty had that apple bottom jeans□
《Low》- Flo Rida & T-Pain（專輯：Mail On Sunday）2009
□穿著毛毛靴□
□Boots with the fur□
□整場人都在看著她□
□The whole club was looking at her□
□她大跳艷舞□
□She hit the floor□
□接下來你會看到□
□Next thing you know□
□辣妹越來越往下露露露露□
□Shorty got low, low, low, low, low, low, low, low□
□TJ，你能搞定這個嗎？□
□TJ, can you handle this?□
□大衛，你能搞定這個嗎？□
□David, can you handle this?□
□克萊爾，你能搞定這個嗎？□
□Clay, can you handle this?□
《Bootylicious》- Destiny's Child（專輯：Survivor）2001
□我認為他們不能搞定這個□
□I don't think they can handle this□
□我不認為你準備好了□
□I don't think you're ready for this jelly□
□I don't think you're ready for this □
□因為寶貝我的身體對你來說太秀色可餐了□
□cause my body's too bootylicious for you, babe□
□我不認為你準備好了□
□I don't think you're ready for this jelly□
□I don't think you're ready for this□
□因為寶貝我的身體對你來說太秀色可餐了□
□cause my body's too bootylicious for you, babe□
□我喜歡大屁股我不能說謊□
□I like big butts and I cannot lie□
《Baby Got Back》- Sir Mix-A-Lot（專輯：Mack Daddy）2002
□你其他的兄弟不能否認□
□You other brothers can't deny□
□當一個大屁股的女孩走過來□
□When a girl walks in With her itty bitty waist□
□你看到一個圓圓的屁股□
□And a round thing in your face□
□你跳起來□
□You get sprung□
□想接近她□
□Wanna pull up front□
□什麼問題問題是□
□What matters□
□是真的在求愛□
□Courtship is real□
□帶你吃一頓飯□
□Take you to a nice hot meal□
□並且打賞服務員消費□
□And I'll tip the waiter□
噢，我的天，停，停，停
Oh, my God, stop! Stop!
怎麼回事？
What was that, yo?
我們遊戲不是這麼玩的
Not how we play the game.
你覺得你是比安東尼雷
You think you're a better lyricist than Sir Mix-a-Lot,
更棒的作詞人？那個被皇后樂隊極力推崇的人？
a man who was knighted by Queen?
- 你知道皇后樂隊嗎？ - 知道
- You know the band Queen? - Yes.
不，先生，我不知道，我只是情不自禁
No, sir, I do not. I just... I couldn't help it.
我看到了天使
I caught a glimpse of an angel.
激發了靈感
I got inspired.
好吧，你們完了
Well, you're going to hell.
那麼，你們完了，因為麻煩鬼樂團
Because, Treblemakers, you gone!
你們出局了
You gone!
- 再見 - 抱歉
- Bye-bye. - Sorry.
抱歉，我真的很抱歉
Sorry. I'm sorry.
還剩下四個組
Four left.
讓我們看看下一個分類
Let's take a look at the next category!
鄉     村     愛     情
有    關    臀    部    的    歌
噢，鄉村愛情
Oh. Country love!
噢，噢，噢，我最擅長這個
Oh! Oh, oh! I am all about this!
這裡沒有人比我更喜歡這個了
Nobody in this room has loved more tender than I have.
選我們！
Please pick us.
讓我來唱
Let me have it.
- 讓我們來唱，讓世界聽見我們的歌聲 - 沒錯！
- Let us have it. Let the world have it. - Yeah!
我要把這個機會給他
I would give it to him.
好了，為什麼不從你開始呢？
All right, then. Well, why don't we start with you?
音調掛鉤樂團，到你們了
Tone Hangers, you're up. You're up.
什麼？
What?
好了，我能想到的，我能想到了
All right, I got this. I got this. I got this.
這是我的即興演奏
This is my jam!
牛仔們，這個怎麼樣？
How about them Cowboys?
□我去參加了空中跳水□
□I went skydiving□
《Live Like You Were Dying》- Tim McGraw （專輯：Live Like You Were Dying）2004
□我去參加了攀登落基山□
□I went rocky mountain climbing□
□我在一條名叫Fumanchu 的公牛□
□I went two point seven seconds□
□背上停留了2.7秒□
□On a bull named Fu Man Chu□
□我變得博愛□
□And I loved deeper□
□我說話變得和善□
□And I spoke sweeter□
□我還□
□And I□
《Before He Cheats》- Carrie Underwood（專輯：Some Hearts）2006
□我用自己的鑰匙□
□I dug my key into the side□
□進到他那輛可愛的車子裡□
□Of his pretty little souped-up four-wheel drive□
□在他的真皮座椅上刻上我的名字□
□Carved my name into his leather seats□
□我用一根路易斯維爾的球棒打碎兩盞車前燈□
□I took a Louisville slugger to both head lights□
□在4個車輪上都戳了個洞□
□I slashed a hole in all four tires□
□也許下次他會想到之前他的那些謊話□
□Maybe next time he'll think before he cheats□
兄弟，加油
Come on, man.
- 我想不出來 - 加油啊
- I got nothing. - Come on!
該死的，夥計們，我想不出來
God damn it! I got nothing, guys!
什麼？
What?
- 對不起 - 你搞砸了
- I'm sorry. - You blew it.
你真讓人失望
Man, you are such a dis-a-ca-pointment.
雷納威爾森蒙克列夫馬修斯四世
Reginald Wilson Moncrieff Matthews IV,
看在上帝的份上，你在幹什麼
what on God's green one are you doing?
我一直在想D小節的那個42歌G調和B調
I had my mind on those 42 G's at D and B's.
- 很遺憾你們必須告別了 - 不！
- I'm afraid you've kissed that goodbye. - No!
- 綠灣包裝工隊 - 不，不，不
- Green Bay Packers... - No, no, no!
- ...你們出局啦 - 不！
- ...you gone! - No!
我們看看下一個曲目分類
Let's see what the next category is!
和     約     翰     梅     爾     約      會
噢
Oh.
太好了！
Yes! Oh!
約翰·梅爾：唯一一個四座格萊美最佳流行男歌手獎在手的樂壇巨星。
噢，我曾經是他的私人助理
Oh, I was his personal assistant!
- 這不公平 - 讓我們來
- Unfair! - Come on.
- 太好了 - 我們來唱這個
- Yes, yep. - We got this.
我們來唱著歌，選我們，選我們
Yeah, we got this. Get in there.
好的，為什麼我們不從達斯發聲機開始呢？
Okay, then why don't we start with you, Das Sound Machine?
《A Thousand Miles》-  Vanessa Carlton（專輯：Best of Vanessa Carlton）2002
瓦妮莎·卡爾頓（Vanessa Carlton）美國獨立創作女歌手，2002-03年間與約翰·梅爾曾是戀人關係
□循著小路往市中心走去 □
□Making my way downtown□
□腳步開始輕盈 □
□Walking fast□
□街上人來人往□
□Faces pass□
□我往家走去 □
□And I'm homebound□
□我們再也不能□
□We are never ever ever□
《We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together》- Taylor Swift（專輯：Red）2012
□一起回到過去了□
□Getting back together□
□我們再也不能□
□We are never ever ever□
□一起回到過去了□
□Getting back together□
泰勒·斯威夫特（Taylor Swift）我霉，和約翰·梅爾同是花心大蘿蔔，2010年間與約翰·梅爾曾是戀人關係
□你讓你的朋友□
□You go talk to your friends□
□跟我的朋友□
□Talk to my friends□
□來說服我□
□Talk to me□
□說服我□
□Talk to□
□但我們真的再也不能□
□But we are never ever ever ever□
□一起回到過去了□
□Getting back together□
□這和愛情有什麼關係□
□What's love got to do□
《What's Love Got to Do With It》- Tina Turner （專輯：What's Love Got To Do With It）1993
□這與愛何干□
□Got to do with it
□這算什麼愛情□
□What's love□
□不過是低等情感□
□But a second hand emotion□
□這和愛情有什麼關係□
□What's love got to do□
□這與愛何干□
□Got to do with it□
□當你清楚真心會破碎的時候□
□Who needs a heart□
□誰還會要存有一顆真心□
□When a heart can be broken□
那是約翰梅爾的歌嗎？
Is that John Mayer?
這不值得倒彩
That doesn't deserve a "boo."
我做到了
I killed that!
給大家解釋一下
Explain for everyone,
因為這聽起來好像是你在暗示
because it sounds like you're implying
約翰梅爾和蒂娜透納在...
that John Mayer and Tina Turner are having...
蒂娜·特納（Tina Turner）1936年出生，沒有和約翰·梅爾相戀過，兩人相差38歲
噢，正是這樣
Oh, yeah.
讓他們出局，讓他們出局
Get them out! Get them out!
我不知道我是否能相信他
I don't know if I believe him.
我說的是實話
I'm telling the truth!
音調掛鉤樂團
Tone Hangers,
你們出局啦！
you gone!
兩隊，我們剩下兩支隊伍
Two! We have our final two!
是時候一決勝負了
Now we have a showdown!
好了，你們都過來
All right, come on in.
最終對決採用面對面的形式
Let's do this face-off style. Okay.
我們來看看最後的歌曲分類
Let's take a look, see what your final category is.
9    0    年    代    嘻    哈    樂
九十年代的嘻哈爵士樂
'90s hip-hop jams!
好了，給你麼所有人一秒鐘的時間
Okay, y'all, take a second to think about it.
時間到了，開始
Time's up! Go!
《This Is How We Do It》- Montell Jordan（專輯：This Is How We Do It）1995
□我們就是這樣做的□
□This is how we do it□
□我有點嘰嘰喳喳，這一切都是因為□
□I'm kinda buzzed and it's all because□
□我們就是這樣做的□
□This is how we do it□
□中南部喜歡的就沒人喜歡□
□South Central does it like nobody does□
□我們就是這樣做的□
□This is how we do it□
□告訴我所有的鄰居你有多少愛好□
□To all my neighbors you got much flavor□
□我們就是這樣做的□
□This is how we do it□
《Doo Wop》- Lauryn Hill（專輯：The Miseducation of Lauryn Hill）1998
□女孩你知道你最好給我小心點□
□Girls you know you'd better watch out□
□有些人只是關於□
□Some guys some guys are only about□
□那件事□
□That thing that thing that thing□
《Poison》- Bell Biv Devoe（專輯：Greatest Hits）2000
□那個女孩就是毒藥□
□That girl is poison□
□永遠不要相信一個大屁股和微笑□
□Never trust a big butt and smile□
□那個女孩就是毒藥□
□That girl is poison□
《Scenario》- A Tribe Called Quest（專輯：The Low End Theory）1996
□我們開始吧□
□Here we go yo□
□有啥□
□So what's□
□那麼什麼是情景□
□So what's the scenario□
□我們開始吧□
□Here we go yo□
□有啥□
□So what's□
□那麼什麼是情景□
□So what's the scenario□
□我們開始吧□
□Here we go□
《Insane in the Brain》- Cypress Hill（專輯：Black Sunday）1998
□在薄膜中瘋狂□
□Insane in the membrane□
□在大腦中瘋狂□
□Insane in the brain□
□在薄膜中瘋狂□
□Insane in the membrane□
□在大腦中瘋狂□
□Insane in the brain□
□當我有了你，我就像擁有一切□
□I got all I need when I got you and I□
□我環顧四周 而我看見了美滿的生活□
□I look around me and see sweet life□
□我被困在黑暗中 但你是我的照明燈□
□I'm stuck in the dark but you're my flashlight□
□你抓著我□
□You're gettin' me□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□Gettin' me through the night□
抱歉
I'm sorry.
能再解釋一遍什麼是九十年代嘻哈爵士樂嗎？
What '90s hip-hop jam is that again?
嗯...
Um...
和二十一世紀即興爵士樂很像
More like a 21 st century jam.
就這樣，嗯，這是我寫的
That's it. Yeah. I wrote it.
保持冷靜
Just stay calm.
你說這是你原創的？
You're saying it's an original?
是的，這是我原創的
Yes, I'm saying it's an original.
噓
Boo!
回家吧，小女孩
Go home, little girl!
即興爵士樂是我們的招牌
Our jam is covers!
我們唾棄原創
We spit on originals!
你叫什麼名字？
What is your name?
艾米莉
Emily.
我恨你
I hate you.
鑒於這個讓人尷尬的
In light of this embarrassing
不專業的事實
and unprofessional information,
我恐怕不得不宣佈
I am forced to declare...
抱歉，大家
I'm sorry, guys.
- 獲勝者是達斯發聲機 - 太好了！
- ...Das Sound Machine is the winner! - Yeah!
嗚呼
Whoo!
棒極了！
Yeah! Yeah!
噢
Oh.
《Jump》- Kris Kross（專輯：Totally Krossed Out）1992
嘿，這真是你寫的？
Hey, did you really write that?
艾米莉，你不應該這樣做
You shouldn't have done that, Emily.
現在達斯發聲機都覺得他們已經佔了上風了
Now DSM thinks that they have the drop on us.
抱歉，我剛才慌了
I'm sorry. I panicked.
我理解你們想讓我爬到岩石底下沒石頭壓死的心情
I understand if you want me to crawl under a rock and die.
嘿，我們不想...
Hey, we don't want...
嘿，我們沒這麼想
Hey, we don't want that.
嘿，貝卡
Hey, Becs,
- 我們去見見綠灣包裝工隊 - 好的
- let's go meet the Green Bay Packers. - Okay.
呃
Whew.
嚇你一跳
Boo!
我只是在開玩笑，你願意過會和我啪啪啪嗎？
I'm just kidding. Would you like to have sex later?
不
No!
所以這個「不」，然後？
So that's a "no," then?
因為說不的時候眨了眼，這是...
Because with the wink, and that's what...
這是百分百的拒絕
It's 100% no!
我想要這個，快給我
I want it! Give me!
達克斯，我發誓，要是那孩子不是我的侄子
Dax. I swear, if this kid was not my nephew...
嘿，我知道你很忙
Hey, I know you're crazy busy,
但你有聽我的樣片嗎？
but have you had a chance to check out those demos?
有，有，有，我聽了
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I did.
我們之間的沉寂是個好的信號
This dead air between us is a good sign.
這樣
Look,
你的耳朵很靈
you got a great ear,
你在錄音室也證實了這一點
you proved that in the booth,
我很高興聽到了你的其他本事
and I was super excited to hear what else you had
你給我的大部分都是串燒音樂
and what you gave me was more mash-ups.
我做的就是這類音樂
That's sort of what I do.
聽著，瑞吉，你是叫瑞吉嗎？
Listen, Reggie. Is it "Reggie"?
我叫貝卡
"Beca."
這種事經常發生
Um, that happens a lot, though. You'd be surprised.
好的
Okay.
事情是這樣的
Here's the thing.
任何會聽音樂，會用電腦的孩子都會做你串燒
Um, any kid with ears and a laptop can do that.
達克斯也能做
Dax can do that.
- 明白嗎 - 明白
- All right? - Right.
如果你只是想成為一名DJ
So that's fine if you want a career
這樣就可以了
deejaying raves out in the desert.
但是如果你想在你的稅單上寫上「音樂製作人」
But if you want to write "music producer" on your tax forms someday,
那你就必須要有原創的作品
then you've gotta have an original voice. Do you understand?
你必須把你的本事展示給我看
You've gotta show me what you have.
現在，我有的只是一張音樂串燒的樣片
Right now, what I have is a demo with mash-ups on it.
對，對
Yeah, yeah.
我有很多話想說，現在我把它們全部留下來
I got lots of stuff to say. I'm just saving it all up.
聽著
Look...
呃...
Uh...
- 你叫什麼? 貝卡？ - 沒錯
- What is it? "Beca"? - Beca.
好的，對
Okay, yeah.
所以說，你實習生
So, you're an intern,
這裡其他的人都是實習生
and everybody else in here is an intern.
你有天賦，這裡的所有人都有天賦
You're talented, everybody else in here is talented.
所以說你的突出點在哪裡？你懂我的意思嘛？
So what the hell makes you special? Do you know what I mean?
很好
That's good.
所以，我要做的是，給你多一次機會
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna give you one more shot
以藝術家的身份向我展現自己，明白嗎
to show me who you are as an artist. Okay?
不要浪費這個機會
Do not waste it.
是的，先生，我不會浪費這個機會的
No, sir, will not waste it.
為了你好，我也希望你不會的
I really hope you don't, for your sake.
因為我不想看到在阿卡貝拉樂團在
'Cause I would hate to think
唱流行樂就是你所有能做的事
that singing covers in an a cappella group is all you can do.
麻煩換一下這些紙巾
Please replace the paper towels.
嘿，這是傑西，有事請發短信
Hey, it's Jesse. Text me.
嘿，是我...
Hey, it's me. Um...
嘿，也許你不會聽到這段信息
Hey, so you might not be able to hear this message,
因為我也許沒有什麼好說的
because, it turns out, I have nothing to say.
嗯...
Um...
在音樂行業這個意思，就是說「我糟透了」
That's music industry speak for "I suck."
你現在肯定睡了
You're definitely asleep right now.
這很好
That's cool.
醒了給我發短信
Text me when you're up.
嘿
Hey.
什麼
What?
難道一個女孩不能去買，然後十四個小時候回來
A girl can't say she's going to grab a smoothie and return 14 hours later?
沒有什麼好懷疑的
There's nothing suspicious about that.
你怎麼這麼晚還沒睡
Why are you up so late anyways?
呃，我剛搞清楚了一些事
Um, I was just figuring some stuff out.
你在現場工作？
You're working on the set?
呃...
Um...
我妹子啊現場工作，我只是
I'm not working on the set. I'm just, like...
什麼？
What?
沒事，沒什麼事了
Nothing. Doesn't matter.
如果你真的想和我這個摯友聊聊的話
If you did wanna share something with me,
我會保密的
your best friend,
我一向嘴巴嚴實
I'm a great keeper of secrets.
就像一個上鎖的保險箱
I'm like a safe that locks,
然後
with a key,
而且鑰匙被藏起來了
and the key is stashed up my bum. Because...
我很好，算了，一切都很好
It's fine. Forget it. It's all good.
所以說這跟你在偷偷的做實習沒有一點關係？
So this has nothing to do with that internship that you sneak off to?
什麼？
What?
- 呃... - 說吧，貝卡
- Um... - Come on, Beca.
你知道每個月我們都會做的那一件事
You know how we do that thing every month
從你錢包裡抽走20塊錢然後你假裝不知道
where I take $20 out of your purse and you pretend not to notice?
我看到了你包裡的工作證
I saw your ID badge in your bag.
不要生氣
Don't be mad.
事實上，我沒生氣
I'm not mad, actually.
關於工作證的事
About the badge.
那些錢，我們等一下再談
The money, I wanna come back to.
噓
Shh.
那你繼續說謊吧
Let's just focus on your lie.
貝卡
Beca,
為什麼你不告訴我們呢？
why didn't you tell us?
或者至少告訴克洛伊
Or at least Chloe.
我不知道，或許這樣更加容易？
I don't know. Just... 'Cause it's just easier.
發生了太多的事情了，要是她覺得
There's, like, so much going on, and Chloe would lose her mind
我的注意了不在世界大賽上，她會瘋掉的
if she thought my sole focus wasn't winning Worlds.
抱歉，我現在只是抓狂了
Sorry, it's just now I'm freaking out,
因為事實證明
because it turns out, like, I'm totally
我完全沒有成為一名音樂製作人的能力
not good enough to be a music producer.
在我進入下半生的時候知道這件事真是太有趣了
Which is cool and fun to know as I enter the rest of my life.
好了，我要在這裡打斷你
Okay, I'm just gonna stop you right there.
你是我認識的最有才華的人
You're the most talented person that I know,
我見過三個搖擺家族的成員
and I've met three of The Wiggles.
親密的
Intimately.
噢
Oh.
貝卡，你知道你有多棒嗎？
Beca, do you know how awesome you are?
你是該死的柏卡米切爾
You're Beca effing Mitchell.
好嗎？
Okay?
你是「超級音樂學士」
You're "The Big B.M."
這就是你
That's you.
你是無與倫比的
And you're awesome!
你需要一些我的自信嗎？
Do you need some of my confidence?
我可能把我的自信降低一級
'Cause I could maybe tone mine down a notch.
好啊
Yeah, okay.
那讓我搓出來一些
Then let me rub some out.
噢，好啊
Oh, okay.
等等，我想你需要多一些
Wait. Think you need a bit more.
這來自哪裡？
It comes from there?
- 好了，謝謝你 - 你需要這個
- Okay. Thank you. - You just need that.
我現在要給你一些好東西
I'm gonna get you the good stuff now.
不，我不想要屁股上的自信
No, I don't want butt confidence.
我不要你屁股上的自信
I don't want your butt confidence!
不，我夠了
No! I have enough!
我夠自信了，我夠自信了
I have enough! I have enough!
我對你有信心，貝卡
I believe in you, Beca.
來吧
Come on.
哇，蠟燭，餐布巾
Whoa. Candles, cloth napkins,
- 除了沙拉還有別的食物 - 沒錯
- foods other than salsa. - Yep.
這筆我們平常約會的方式更好一些
This is a little classier than our typical hook-ups.
不是嗎？
Is it? Huh.
我有法式蛋糕
I have a patisserie,
一些熟食
some charcuterie,
還有一大碗進口的刺山柑
and a huge bowl of exotic capers.
我不知道這些是什麼，看起來像是鹽漬青豆
I didn't know what those were, but they're like salty peas.
那麼
So,
我不知道你最近有沒有看新聞
I don't know if you've seen the news lately,
有場戰爭
but there's a war.
還有，經濟...
And also, the economy
在下降，衰退，上漲
is dipping and ebbing and flowing.
邦博，怎麼了？
Bumper, what's going on?
現在你有點嚇著我了
Now you're kind of creeping me out.
好吧，我想我會說明白的
Okay, I guess I'll just lay it all out there.
今晚我把你帶到這裡的原因是...
The reason that I brought you here tonight
是因為我在想
was because I was thinking that
也許，可能...
maybe, perhaps,
要是你有興趣的話...
if you're interested...
這比我預想的要難
This is harder than I thought it was gonna be.
我想和你約會
I wanna date you.
這就是我的想法
That's what I want.
就是，認真的，像真的情侶一樣
Like for real. Like a real couple.
我們一起走出去，拉著手
Where we, like, go out in public and hold hands
一起騎單車
and ride bikes together.
或者我們一起去果園，摘蘋果
Or we, like, go to an orchard and pick apples.
又或者我們一起去
Or we, like, do one of those, like,
熊寶寶工作坊
Build-A-Bear Workshops together,
一起製作熊寶寶玩偶
and we build bears,
然後給一個取名叫「邦博」，另一個叫「胖艾米」
and you name one "Bumper" and I'll name one "Fat Amy,"
你的玩偶會比我的大，那會很可愛
and yours will be bigger than mine and it'll be cute,
我們可以把它們擺在我們的床頭
and we can put them on our bed that we share.
你覺得怎麼樣？
What do you say?
不
No.
我不能...
I don't...
我不能這樣做
I don't do that.
好的，沒問題
Yeah, that's cool.
- 這個想法太... - 還好
- It was a... - Cool.
- 這個想法太蠢了 - 嗯
- It was a stupid idea anyways. - Yeah.
很明顯我們不應該那麼做，我們應該
Obviously, we shouldn't do that. We should just
回到過去那樣
go back to how things used to be
而去我要把我買的昂貴的食物全部吃掉
and just go at it on top of all this expensive food that I bought.
你在哭嗎？
Are you crying?
沒有
Nope.
不，我沒有
No, I'm not.
邦博
Bumper!
行了，你不是認真的
Come on, you can't be serious.
我不能安定下來
I can't be tied down by anything.
我是個流浪者
I'm on a walkabout.
我是脫韁的野馬
I'm a free-range pony that can't be tamed.
你明白的
You know.
- 好的 - 我就像煙花一樣
- Okay. - I'm like a firework.
- 不可能安定下來的 - 好吧
- I can't be tied down. - Okay.
那就這樣了，我猜我們就這樣了，對嗎？
Then that's it. Then I guess that's it, right?
因為我不會像這樣繼續下去
Because I'm not gonna keep going on like this.
- 呃... - 很好
- Well... - Fine.
很好，如果這就是你的想法，我想我們完了
Fine, if that's how you feel, then I think we're done.
我們的關係結束了
I think it's over.
- 就這樣？ - 就這樣
- That's it? - That's it, then.
所以關係結束了
So it's over, then.
對，這就結束了
Fine. Then it's over.
很好
Fine, then.
不！
No!
太遲了，你們來太遲了
Too late. You're too late!
我們還沒有唱過小夜曲
I figured when we didn't do the serenade,
伴奏應該會挑逗她
the back-up plan should be to play her off.
劃回去，回去
Turn around. Go back.
我不想再聽到一點聲音
I don't wanna hear another peep!
人生中的煩惱
Trebles for life
- 本傑 - 抱歉
- Benji! - I'm sorry.
嘿，姐妹們，這是我的首次表演
Hey, guys, it's my first performance.
冷靜，這只是我們進軍世界大賽的一次綵排
Calm down. It's just a chance for us to rehearse for Worlds.
我敢說，這只是一群老傢伙
As far as I can tell, it's just for a bunch of old people.
外面坐滿了人
There's a full house out there.
我們是怎樣得到這個演出機會的？
How did we get this gig again?
他們打電話給我們的
They called us.
姐妹們，你知道嗎？
You know what, guys?
我知道我們在嘗試新的花式
I know we're trying a lot of new stuff, but I feel like we're gonna get out there
但我們要走上台去感受那種能量，但後搞定一切
and we're gonna feel the energy and we are just gonna nail all of it!
抱歉，辮子扎得太緊了
Sorry, these braids are so tight.
你知道嗎？我不知道
You know what? I don't know. I don't know.
我有很多疑問
I have many, many doubts,
因為如果我們這次失敗了，我們就贏不了世界大賽
because if we fail this, then we won't win the Worlds,
如果贏不了世界大賽，貝拉樂團就
and if we don't win the Worlds, there will be no more Bellas,
不存在了
and without the Bellas,
沒有了貝拉樂團，我就沒有了人生
then my life would have had no...
"瘧疾"
"Malaria."
請定義"瘧疾" ，弗洛.
"Meaning," Flo.
三、二...
Three, two...
嘿，大家好，歡迎回到《一起來合唱》
Hey, everybody. Welcome back to Let's Talk-Appella,
可便攜式播客版本
the portable podcast edition.
我們繼續關注生死未卜的貝拉樂團
We are following the story of the embattled Barden Bellas
是如何自我拯救的
on their road to redemption.
女裡掙扎著重獲公眾的喜愛
Trying to crawl their way back into the public's affection.
要是她們能夠不再
And if they can just hold off
向我們展示她們的私處
showing us any more of their genitalia,
那麼也許她們就能夠參加世界大賽了
they may make it to the World Championship.
呃，那畫面至今仍然
Well, I can't un-see it.
在我腦中揮之不去
It's haunted me ever since.
這是那張照片
Well, there's a picture of it right here.
不，約翰，這不應該是你的屏保
No. This should not be your screensaver, John.
走上舞台的是巴頓貝拉樂團
Stepping onto the stage, the Barden Bellas.
《Promises》- Skrillex & Nero Remix（單曲專輯：Promises）2011
□你讓我如此的狂野□
□You got me so wild□
□我怎能否認□
□How can I ever deny□
□你讓我如此之高□
□You got me so high□
□高得我感覺不到火焰□
□So high I cannot feel the fire□
□你不停的告訴我□
□And you keep telling me□
□告訴我 你會很貼心□
□Telling me that you'll be sweet□
□你永遠不會想要離開我的身邊□
□And you'll never want to leave my side□
□只要我不打破這些□
□As long as I don't break these□
□我仍然覺得承諾如此浪費在自己□
□Promises, and they still feel all so wasted on myself□
- 哇- 不錯
- Whoa! - All right!
- 這讓人有些興奮 - 太時髦了
- This is some exciting stuff. - So sassy!
□我是你夢中的女孩□
□I'm your dream girl□
《Problem》- Natalia Kills（專輯：Trouble）2013
□這是真正的愛□
□This is real love□
□但你知道他們怎麼說我□
□But you know what they say about me□
□那女孩是個問題□
□That girl is a problem□
□女孩是個問題□
□Girl is a problem□
□他們仍然覺得如此浪費在自己□
□They still feel all so wasted on myself□
□汗水□
□Sweat□
□滴在你胸上□
□Dripping down your chest□
□想你的紋身□
□Thinking 'bout your tattooed knuckles□
□躺在我大腿上的男孩□
□On my thigh boy boy boy□
□涼爽□
□Cold□
□你沒有淋浴□
□Shower you got no□
□控制的力量□
□Power to control□
□我如何讓你我的玩具□
□How I make you my toy toy toy□
□我的臀部搖擺□
□My hips rocking□
□隨著我們繼續緊閉嘴巴□
□As we keep lip locking□
哇啊，太精彩了
Wow. A lot going on up there.
我覺得現在聽起來還不錯
I think this sounds good.
說實話，約翰，我的感官現在得到了滿足
Honestly, my senses are overwhelmed here, John.
也許他們想要降低舞台效果
They might wanna tone down the theatrics.
希望她們不要有道具
Let's hope there are no props.
噢，她們把道具拿出來了，約翰
Oh, they brought the props out, John.
看她們的道具
And there are the props.
比起阿卡貝拉，這更像馬戲團表演
This is more of a circus act than an a cappella performance.
蓋爾，好像貝拉樂團
Gail, it's as if the Barden Bellas
已經搞不清她們自己的定位了
just don't know who they are anymore.
□噢寶貝□
□Oh baby□
□你是個壞男孩□
□You so bad boy□
□讓我瘋狂的壞男孩□
□Drive me mad boy□
□你不在乎他們怎麼說我的□
□But you don't care when they say about me□
□那女孩是個問題□
□That girl is a problem□
□女孩是個問題□
□Girl is a problem□
哇！
Whoa!
看這個
Look at this!
她著火了，她著火了
She's on fire! She's on fire!
- 噢，我的天，我著火了- 現在她們把一個人點著了
- Oh, my God! I'm on fire! - Now they lit one on fire.
- 天啊，上帝 - 噢！
- Good day! Good heavens! - Oh.
- 我來了 - 噢，我的天，我不能呼吸啦
- Incoming! - Oh, my God, I can't breathe!
我不能呼吸了，胖艾米，我不能呼吸了
I can't breathe, girl! Fat Amy, I can't breathe!
看來她們沒什麼機會能打敗達斯發聲機樂團了
Beating DSM seems impossible for this team.
即使連普通人也能明白
Even these common people can see
巴頓貝拉樂團是沒有機會解禁得了
that the Barden Bellas have no shot at reinstatement.
她們是阿卡貝拉界的恥辱
They are an embarrassment
這就是她們所代表的意思
to a cappella and all that it stands for.
這就是你們把姑娘們送到大學會發生的事
This is what happens when you send girls to college.
是嗎？
Is it?
這是上課要用的？
Is that for a class?
不是，當我感到壓抑
No, it's just when I get stressed, words sort of flow right out of me
字詞從我腦中飛出，我把它們 拍成句子，寫成歌
and I try and channel them in my songwriting...
你們要忽略剛剛發生的事情嗎？
Are we just gonna ignore what happened back there?
大家，你們在聽嗎？
Guys, hello?
世界大賽就在離我們一步之遙的地方
The Worlds are right around the corner
你們卻表現的像我們剛剛沒有吃下一大袋...啊啊！
and you guys are acting like we didn't just eat a big bag of... Ahhh!
你為什麼對著我大喊大叫
Why are you yelling at me?
因為你，我剛才差點被燒死
I almost burned to death because of you a-ca-bitches.
你差點被燒死，是因為你站的位置不對
If you almost died, it was only because you were standing in the wrong spot.
不，是弗洛把我推過去的
No! Flo flipped into me!
當然，要怪少數人咯
Sure. Blame the minority.
我是黑人而且還是女同性戀
I'm black, gay, and a woman.
我不會指責任何一個人的
I'm not pointing the finger at anybody.
是艾米莉的錯
It was Legacy's fault.
我？等等，我沒有...
Me? Wait, I didn't...
很明顯我們沒有機會在達斯發聲機擅長的領域打敗他們了
Obviously, we're not gonna beat Das Sound Machine at their game.
我們需要一個新的計劃，現在就要
So we need a new plan. Like, now.
像這樣的情況，我們只有一條路可走
At times like these, there's only one thing for us to do.
- 假死然後逃到鄉下 - 很接近
- Fake your own death and flee the country. - Close.
我們要去休閒訓練營
We're going on a retreat.
聽著，我覺得這是一個好主意
Look, I think the retreat will be a good thing.
你們應該繼續朝著全國大賽努力
You girls need to bond heading into Worlds.
這會很有趣
It'll be so much fun.
我不知道，不，媽媽，這太糟糕了...
I don't know. No, Mom, it's bad. It's...
- 這些女孩在互相指責 - 噢，沒什麼大不了的
- The girls are yelling at each other. - Oh, big deal.
我記得我曾經給你的教母
I remember putting your godmother,
瑪姬皮斯托爾一個鎖喉
Maggie Pistol, in a choke hold,
因為她堅持認為喬治邁克爾是同性戀
because she insisted that George Michael was gay.
- 誰？- 噢
- Who? - Oh.
我只是擔心，我正在貝拉樂團的時光
I'm just worried that my entire Bella career
會成為那段糟糕的表演
will be that one terrible performance.
而去我永遠不能在林肯中心獨唱，你明白嗎？
And I'll never get to solo at Lincoln Center, you know?
但是你回去歐洲
But you're gonna get to go to Europe.
這將會是我大學生涯中的自高峰
That would have been the highlight of my college career.
你們可以贏
And you girls can win it.
你們必須贏
You have to win it.
你們讓貝拉樂團的聲音變得如此美妙
You just made being a Bella sound so amazing.
沒錯
And it is amazing.
這種姐妹情誼將會支撐著你們走完下半生
It's a sisterhood that is gonna support you for the rest of your life.
我知道你們現在沒感覺
I know you're not feeling it,
但是你們會感受到的
but you will.
這不會是貝拉樂團的終點
This won't be the end of the Bellas.
嘿，本傑
Hey, Benji.
艾米莉
Emily!
- 聽著，我覺得這裡少了個字 - 是嗎？
- Listen, I think you're missing a word here. - What's that?
噢，天啊，不，我不是...這個意思
Oh, God. No. That's not... That isn't what I meant. I just...
我也這麼覺得
I didn't think so.
- 這真讓人尷尬 - 這看起來
- That's really embarrassing. - No, it looks...
句法一直是我的強項
Syntax is usually my forte,
- 這不應該 - 其實這看起來挺好的
- so I don't know how that happened. - Well, it looks great.
謝謝你，這真是太好了...
Thank you. That's really sweet...
呃...
Um...
要是我手上沒有螢光漆
When my hands aren't covered in glitter paint,
也許我們能再試一次？
do you think maybe we could try that again?
當然
Yeah. Sure.
好的，好了，嗯...
All right. Okay. Well...
我期待那一刻的到來
I'll look forward to that.
只是，你懂的
Just, you know,
- 把手洗乾淨的時候告訴我一聲 - 這個
- let me know when they're clean. - That's...
- 我會的 - 好的
- I will. - All right.
- 我肯定會的 - 好的
- You bet. - Okay.
玩得開心
All right. Have a good one.
好的，姑娘們，快上車
Okay, girls! Everyone, in the bus.
走，走，走!
Go, go, go!
- 出發咯 - 好的
- Let's go. - Okay.
繫好安全帶
Seatbelts!
祝你好運，本傑
Good luck, Benji!
這個地方真漂亮
This place is sweet!
不錯的地方，對吧
It's nice, right?
我要找一個地方給我的電腦充電
I need to find somewhere to charge my laptop.
你是怎麼知道這個地方的？
How'd you hear about this place?
我們這裡
From yours truly.
你們好，貝拉們
Hello, Bellas.
奧布莉
Aubrey!
- 奧布莉 - 奧布莉
- Aubrey! - Aubrey!
好了，姑娘們
Okay, girls.
噢，哇，嗨，你一定是艾米莉了
Oh, wow. Hi! You must be Emily.
- 嘿，嘿 - 嘿，你好
- Hey, hey. - Hey. Hi.
歡迎來到落葉山林小屋
Welcome to The Lodge at Fallen Leaves,
排名錢500強的公司吧員工送來這裡
where Fortune 500 companies send
培訓他們的團隊合作能力
their employees to build teamwork skills.
你在運營這個地方？
You run this whole place?
我發現我擅長發號施令，改變人們的意志
You know, I realized I had a knack for barking orders and bending people's will.
所以我把它發展成了我的事業
So I made a career out of it.
這讓我想起
Which reminds me,
站成一派，貝拉們
fall in line, Bellas!
她一點也沒有變
She ain't changed.
打起精神來，別閒逛
No slouching! No straggling!
我看見你了，傑西卡
I see you, Jessica.
我感到極大的悲傷和悔恨
It is with great sorrow and regret
看到我們曾經驕傲的組織
that I had to watch our once proud organization
變成國家恥辱
become a national disgrace!
能給我小冰箱的密碼嗎？
Can I have the keys to the minibar?
閉嘴
Zip it.
世界大賽是我們重獲成功的機會
The Worlds signifies a shot at redemption.
除非你們再次找回你們的聲音，否則你們將無望再贏
You don't have a chance at winning until you find your sound again.
你們完全失去了你們的和諧
You have totally lost your harmony!
所以，在接下來的兩天裡
So, for the next two days,
你們要時刻呆在一起，直到你們找回和諧
you will be doing everything together until you regain it.
女士們，準備好蛻變吧
Ladies, get ready to be transformed.
貝拉同伴的力量和驕傲女性的傳統
You are surrounded with the strength of your fellow Bellas
支撐環繞著你們
and the support of a proud female tradition.
而去周圍有一些捕熊陷阱
And a few dozen bear traps.
所以不要偏離做著記號的小路
So don't stray too far from the marked paths.
- 好了，很好，我們出發吧 - 好的
- Okay, great, let's go! - All right.
呃，也許我應該先泡個熱水澡
Well, maybe I'll just start with a hot shower,
再來個小小的足底按摩
maybe a little foot rub.
胖艾米，這裡沒有房間給你住
Fat Amy, there are no guest rooms for you.
那我們住哪裡
Then where are we staying?
我不懂露營
I don't understand camping.
我們自願像狗一眼生存
We're voluntarily living like dogs.
這是最糟的事
This is the worst.
我們現在呼吸的空氣至少百分之九十都是屁
The air we're breathing right now is at least 90% fart.
這提醒了我
That reminds me,
我要去上廁所
I need to see a man about a horse.
噢
Oh!
有人有多餘的衛生紙嗎？
Did anyone happen to pack a spare roll of toilet paper?
- 或者濕巾 - 沒有
- Or a moist towelette? - Nope.
又沒人有襯衫，最小號的
Anyone have a T-shirt, size extra-small?
好了，帳篷那邊就是
Okay. Side of the tent it is.
我們來這裡幹嘛
What are we doing here?
我們要重新結合在一起
We're bonding.
你看起來渾身經崩崩的，要來一個背部按摩嗎
You seem so tense. Do you need a back rub?
好幾個部位在按摩我的背，謝謝
Several body parts are rubbing my back right now, thank you.
貝卡，我們非常親密
You know, Beca, we're very close,
但這次活動會讓我們
but I feel like this retreat is really gonna let us
一起瞭解對方
discover everything about each other.
對嗎？
Is that right?
你知道嗎，我最後悔的事是
You know, one of my biggest regrets
在學校沒有做足實驗
is that I didn't do enough experimenting in college.
你這奇怪
You're so weird.
謝謝誇獎
Thanks.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
我希望太陽永遠不要升起
I hope the sun never comes up.
為什麼我會拿到旅行氣枕
Why do I get the travel pillow?
是你在摸我嗎？
Were you touching my goodies?
是的
Yes.
噢，姐妹們，我有點...
Oh, guys, I've got a little... It won't...
我需要幫忙把這個弄出來
I just need some help getting it out.
你能唱點什麼嗎？
Can you sing something?
這根管子有點堵
The pipe's a bit blocked.
謝謝，克洛伊
Thanks, Chloe.
這在搞什麼？
What kind of white shit is this?
像凍酸奶一樣暢通無阻
Coming out like froyo now.
《Torn》- Natalie Imbruglia（專輯:Left Of The Middle）1998
貝拉成員，都起來了，快點，我們走
Up and at 'em, Bellas! Come on! Let's go!
走啦，快起床，出發啦
Let's go! Let's wake up! Let's do this!
快點，加快步伐，快點
Come on! Pick up the pace, girls!
快點
Come on!
今天我們要重新從基礎做起
Today we are going back to the basics
再次學習怎樣重新從基礎做起
to re-learn how to sing as a group,
同時也要忍受要命的團隊信任感培訓訓練
while also enduring death-defying team-building trust exercises.
這真是好主意
What a great idea!
好了，我們開始吧
Okay, so let's begin.
□他是來自芝加哥的著名小號手□
□He was a famous trumpet man from out Chicago way□
來吧
Come on.
《Boogie Woogie Bugle Boy》- The Andrews Sisters 1940年左右的老歌
□他有一個不羈風格□
□He had a boogie style□
□沒有人能這樣演奏□
□That no one else could play□
□他的技術無人能比□
□He was the top man at his craft□
□他的年齡變大了□
□But then his number came up□
□帶著他的樂章消失了□
□And he was gone with the draft□
□他現在在部隊□
□He's in the army now□
□為新兵吹起床號□
□He's blowing reveille□
□他是第二部隊中不羈的號手□
□He's the boogie woogie bugle boy of company B□
□你無法催促愛情快點到來□
□Oh you can't hurry love□
《You Can't Hurry Love》- Phil Collins（專輯：Hits）2006
□是的 你只能等待□
□No you just have to wait□
相信你的隊員
Trust your team!
□她說愛情來之不易□
□She said love don't come easy□
□但它卻是一場取與捨的遊戲□
□t's a game of give and take□
- 小小，胖艾米 - 把我翻過去
- Careful, Fat Amy! - Turn me over!
快點，要是午餐了
Come on, lunch!
□嘿 姐們，上啊 姐們□
□Hey sister go sister□
《Lady Marmalade》- LaBelle（專輯：Nightbirds）1974
□魂兒 姐們，上啊 姐們□
□Soul sister go sister□
□這兒哪 哦 也 也□
□Giuchie giuchie ya ya dada□
□Giuchie giuchie ya ya here□
□這兒□
□Here□
她說她是亞洲的耶穌
She says she's Asian Jesus.
□混血女郎Marmalade□
□Creole lady marmalade□
《MMMBop》- Hanson（專輯：Middle of Nowhere）1997
□現在是時候了細分□
□And now it's time for a breakdown□
《My Lovin'》- En Vogue（專輯：Funky Divas Remixes）1992
□永遠不會得到它□
□Never gonna get it□
棒極了
Great.
距離完成目標還有兩部
Okay, that was two steps away from being almost fine.
抱歉，我們在幹什麼
Sorry, what are we doing?
我們在重新寫找回我們的聲音
We're rediscovering our sound.
是嗎？
Are we?
因為我覺得我們唱歌永遠唱不到一塊去
'Cause it feels like we're just singing songs that would never go in our set.
貝卡，別說了
Beca, come on.
我們沒有人直到怎麼打敗達斯發聲機
No, none of us know how to beat Das Sound Machine,
但是這樣做下去是不行的
but I know it's not gonna be by doing this.
貝卡，這只是找回和諧訓練
This is just an exercise in finding harmony, Beca.
欲要立之，必先破之
Sometimes you have to break things down before you can build them back up again.
我有更重要的事情去做
I've got more important things to do!
還有什麼比這更重要
What could be more important than this?
沒事，算了吧
Nothing. Forget it.
不，你覺得我們沒發現
No, you don't think that we haven't all realized
你最近一直遲到早退嗎？
you've been a little checked-out lately?
來吧，貝卡，告訴她
Come on, Beca, just tell her.
我聽到了
I heard that.
告訴我什麼
Tell me what?
噢，你誤解了，我很清楚的再說...
Oh, you misunderstood me. I clearly said...
聽著，我不想和你們吵架
Listen, I don't want you guys to fight.
你們是貝卡和克洛伊。合起來是「布藝」
You're Beca and Chloe. Together you're "Bloe."
每個人都喜歡好的布藝
And everyone loves a good bloe.
所以...
So...
好啦
Okay.
我一直在一個錄音室實習
I've been interning at a recording studio
然後一個製作人想聽聽我的作品
and a legit music producer wants to hear my work.
我在外面做的事
God forbid I have something going on outside this group.
好的
Okay.
那為什麼你要向我們隱瞞這件事
So why would you keep something like that from us?
因為你都癡迷在世界大賽上！你們都是。
'Cause you're obsessed! You all are.
考慮到馬上要畢業了，我是唯一一個在考慮畢業後生活的
We're graduating, and the only person thinking about life after the Bellas is me.
專心於貝拉樂團有什麼不對
What is so wrong with being focused on the Bellas?
七年來這一直是我的家
This has been my family for seven years.
對，因為你害怕離開
Yeah, 'cause you're too scared to leave!
成熟點吧
Sack up, dude!
女孩吵架
Girl fight!
那你這一整個學年來都在隨我們撒謊
Okay, so you've been lying to us for the entire year
現在又準備放我們鴿子？
and now you're just gonna flake out?
而去還在擔心世界大賽之後的事？
Now you're gonna flake out when the Worlds is, like, right after graduation?
噢，天哪，我受夠了什麼世界大賽了
Oh, my God! Enough about the Worlds! I...
我要離開這裡
I'm out of here.
你打算就這麼走了？
Oh, okay, you're just gonna leave now?
我們最終都要離開
We all have to, eventually, Chloe!
為什麼就不能是現在
It might as well be now!
等等，貝卡
Wait, Beca...
如果你們自己會想，你們就會跟我走了
If you all knew what was good for you, you'd follow me.
貝卡，看標記
Beca, the sign!
噢，我的天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
噢，不，貝卡，貝卡
Oh, no, Beca! Beca!
什麼鬼？我卡住了
What the hell? I'm stuck!
我被吊住了，我頭昏眼花，我頭昏眼花
I'm stuck! I'm seeing spots! I'm seeing spots!
好了，好了，好了
Well, well, well.
看看現在誰需要我們的幫助
Look who needs our help.
這樣可不好啊，姐妹們
Not cool, guys!
不，不好的是你，把自己的挫敗推到我們頭上來
No, what's not cool is you taking out your frustrations on us!
真的嗎？這就是你現在要說的？
Really? That's what you're gonna say to me right now?
救救我，我要死了，我要死了
Help me! I'm dying! I'm dying!
W我們要把她弄下來，我們需要一個梯子
We need to get her down! We need a ladder!
- 不，我們不相信什麼梯子 - 什麼？
- No, we don't believe in ladders. - What?
他們說等級制度
They suggest a corporate hierarchy
會對我的訓練產生反效果
that is counter-productive to my team-building program.
你們這開的是什麼機構
What kind of operation are you running here?
說真的，你們這整個地方都是陷阱
Seriously, this whole place is, like, full of booby traps!
你才怎樣
And guess what?
笨蛋應該永遠都不會掉進陷阱
Boobs should never be trapped!
除非你在背出毛病的時候支撐你一把
Unless it's for support if you have lower back issues.
好吧，如果我死了，我很抱歉
Okay! If I'm about to die, I'm sorry!
我不是真的那個意思
I didn't mean any of that stuff I said!
我愛你們，愛你們這群呆子
I love all of you! I love all of you awesome nerds,
我喜歡成為貝拉的成員
and I love being a Bella. I'm just so stressed out right now...
- 噢，天啊 - 噢，上帝
- Oh, my God! - Oh, my gosh!
傑西卡和艾希莉，我分不清你們兩個
Jessica and Ashley, I don't actually know which one of you is which.
- 我是傑西卡- 我是傑西卡
- I'm Jessica! - I'm Jessica!
別著急，我們會把你放下來的
Don't worry, we're gonna get you down! Focus up.
- 排好隊形，集中注意，我們能做到的 - 好的
- Get in formation, we can do this. Flo, get up. - Okay.
- 胖艾米，上 - 是的
- Fat Amy, come on! - Yes!
專心點，齊心協力
Let's focus. Work together as a team.
別急，貝卡，我們...
Don't worry, Beca, we got...
她還活著
She's alive.
我像個蝙蝠一樣倒掛著睡覺
I sleep upside down like a bat.
事情真是變化的太快了
It's just everything's changing so fast
我把所有的壓力放在自己身上，你們明白嗎
and I'm putting all this pressure on myself, you know?
我不想失敗
I don't wanna fail.
但是你告訴了我們
But if you just would have said something...
是的，我懂，但是我覺得這樣做很奇怪
Yeah, I know. But I'm weird about that stuff.
我覺得自己能搞定，但是其實我不能
I thought I could figure it out on my own, and I can't.
也許我本來內心沒什麼要說的
Maybe I don't have anything original to say.
我希望能像你一樣
I wish I could do what you do.
至少，我跟你感覺一樣
Well, I feel the same way about you.
你那麼出色，令人生畏
You're so good, it's intimidating.
我想做的是成為你們中的一員
All I've ever wanted is to be one of you.
不是一名後代，二是一名真正的貝拉成員
Not a Legacy, but a Bella.
- 你是一名真正的貝拉成員 - 你當然是一名真正的成員
- You are a real Bella. - Of course you're a Bella.
你是我們中的一員，你交了入團費
You are one of us. You paid the registration fee.
這是一輩子的事，姐妹們
That's for life, dude.
你們想就某個事合作起來嗎？
Do you wanna collaborate on something?
等等，你是認真的
Wait. Are you being serious?
是的
Yeah.
耶
Yeah!
哇哦
Wow!
噢，當然，今晚誰還感覺像個贏家
Man! Yes! Who else feels like a winner tonight?
我知道我看起來不像
I know it doesn't seem like it,
但是我也在恐懼
but I'm afraid, too.
害怕繼續向前，害怕畢業
To move on, to graduate.
這真是太恐怖了
It's really scary.
嗯，你看起來真的挺害怕的
Yeah, it actually does seem like it,
因為你總是把它憋在心中
because you're barely holding it together.
克洛伊，你不應害怕
Well, it doesn't have to be scary, Chloe.
當我快畢業的時候，我從未想過自己
When I was graduating, I never pictured myself
會在森林裡開訓練營
running a retreat in the middle of the woods,
但是我現在在這裡
but here I am.
相信自己能夠處理好某些嚴重控制欲的人
Take it from someone who has dealt with some serious control issues.
就像我爸爸說的那樣
Like my dad always said,
「在人生的雷區
in the minefield of life,
你必須準備好失去兩條腿
you must be prepared to lose both feet.
我相信你懂我的意思的
And I think you all know what I mean.
我不懂
I don't.
那就這麼決定了
Then it's decided.
今年我會畢業
This year I will graduate.
世界大賽將會是我的謝幕表演
The Worlds will be my swan song.
說真的，我要追尋我的理想
I mean it. I'll pursue my passion.
我要叫平困兒童如何唱歌
I'll teach underprivileged children how to sing,
或者我回去跳脫衣舞
or I'll dance exotically.
什麼掙錢多我做什麼
Whatever offers the most money.
呦，你們聽我說
Yo, check this out.
我要搬道緬因州結婚
I'm moving to Maine to get hitched.
你們所有人都來參加我的婚禮
And all y'all can come.
所有人都被邀請了
Everybody's invited.
好好好
Yes, yes, yes.
好了，大家，別說話了，我告訴你們
Okay, okay, guys. Stop asking. I'll tell you.
我畢業後，可能會被驅逐出境
So, after I graduate there's a chance I will be deported.
我會再次嘗試進入這個國家
I will try to re-enter this country,
但我可能會死在海上
but I will probably die at sea.
所以說為今晚而活，是的！
So, let's live for tonight! Yes!
耶!
Yeah!
- 耶！ - 沒錯
- Yes! - All right.
莉莉，你有什麼計劃
Lilly, any plans?
我打算時空旅行
Just gonna travel through time.
當我回顧今天的時候
You know, when I look back on this,
我不會記得那些精彩的表演和比賽
I won't remember performing and competing.
但是我會記住你們這群怪胎的
I'm gonna remember you weirdos.
想想我們永遠不會像這樣
It makes me really sad to think
再聚到一起，就十分傷心
it won't ever be like this again.
我會想念你們的
I'm gonna miss you guys.
- 我也是 - 我也是
- Me, too. - Me, too.
對，我也是
Yeah. Me, too.
□我已拿到長途旅行的通行證□
□I got my ticket for the long way 'round□
《Cups》- Anna Kendrick 即主角貝卡（專輯：Pitch Perfect Soundtrack）2012
□帶上兩瓶威士忌□
□Two bottle of whiskey for the way□
□希望途中有個旅伴□
□And I sure would like some sweet company□
□明天就啟程你覺得如何□
□And I'm leaving tomorrow, wha-do-ya say?□
□當我離去後□
□When I'm gone□
□我走後你會想念我的□
□You're gonna miss me when I'm gone□
□你會想念我的髮香□
□You're gonna miss me by my hair□
□你會時刻想念我的□
□You're gonna miss me everywhere, oh□
□我走後你一定會想念我的□
□You're gonna miss me when I'm gone□
我們剛剛找到了我們的和聲？
Did we just find our sound?
我想是的
I think we did.
我在這裡的工作完成了
My work here is done.
謝謝你
Thank you.
胖艾米，你沒有說過你畢業後打算做什麼
Fat Amy, you never told us what you were gonna do after graduation.
呃，這個...
Oh. Well...
呃.
Mmm.
我沒有任何計劃
No, I don't have any plans.
因為你們知道我這個人只喜歡活在當下
'Cause you guys know me, I just love living in the moment.
艾希莉，你有什麼打算...
Ashley, what are you gonna do after...
事實上，雖然
Actually, though,
如果我們能停下來，真正的想
if we were to stop and really think,
「胖艾米未來能做什麼？」
"What could Fat Amy be capable of in the future?"
我會告訴你
I'll tell you guys.
我會住到一些混亂的地區，例如塔爾薩或者小巖城
I'd be living somewhere, like, sick, like Tulsa or Little Rock.
到時候我將會是一名公司活動中專業的摔跤選手
By day, I'm a professional jelly wrestler for corporate events.
然後每一個晚上
And then, every night,
我能和我的未婚夫邦博抱在一起
it's just me cuddled up with my fiance, Bumper, and...
噢，等等
Oh, wait.
我愛上邦博了
I'm in love with Bumper.
- 嗯嗯 - 沒錯
- Mmm-hmm. - Yeah.
我做了一些不好的事
Okay, I've done something terrible,
我說的不是向克洛伊和貝卡放屁那件事
and I'm not talking about crop-dusting Chloe and Beca right now.
我為此道歉
Apologize for that.
姐們們，我現在要走了
You guys, I need to go right now.
我要重新找回我的男人的心
And I need to win back my man!
去你的判斷
Screw your judgments!
把他追回來，胖艾米
Go get him, Fat Amy!
姐妹們，發生什麼事了？
Guys, what happened?
自己甩下來，艾米
Shake it off, Amy.
這真糟糕
That was bad.
有人給我拿塊餅乾好嗎？
Somebody bring a s'more.
我把我們下個專輯的首發曲發給你
I give you our next album cover.
看看他
Look at him!
今天的工作全都是我一個人做的
I did it all myself today.
現在，我知道我只有一票...
Now, I know that I only have one vote...
你沒有投票權，你不是樂團成員...
You got no votes, man. You're not in the group, so...
好吧，這真傷我的心
Okay, well, that hurts my feelings.
事實就是這樣
It's just the truth, is the thing.
這真傷我的心
Well, that hurts my feelings.
我決定把我的一票投給那頭豬
With my vote, I vote "no" to the pig
把贊成票投給這位光榮的人
and "yes" to this gloriousness.
- 很好，我們待會投票的時候算進去 - 不
- Yeah, it's great. We'll put it to a vote. - No.
邦博，我來了
Bumper, I'm coming!
□很多次我想告訴你□
□Many times I've tried to tell you□
《We Belong》- Pat Benatar（專輯：Best Shots）1989
□很多時候我獨自哭了□
□Many times I've cried alone□
□我總是很驚訝你是多麼的好□
□Always I'm surprised how well you□
□傷害我入骨□
□Cut my feelings to the bone□
□真的不想離開你□
□Don't wanna leave you really□
□我已經投入了太多的時間□
□I've invested too much time□
□忘掉你是多麼的簡單□
□To give you up that easy□
□複雜的心中的疑惑□
□To the doubts that complicate your mind□
□我們屬於光線□
□We belong to the light□
□我們屬於雷□
□We belong to the thunder□
別過來，轉回去
Nope! Turn it around!
□我們屬於聲音□
□We belong to the sound of the words□
□我們都在墮落□
□We've both fallen under□
□無論我們否認或擁抱□
□Whatever we deny or embrace□
□更好或更壞□
□For worse or for better□
我不想見到你
I don't wanna see you!
□我們都應該□
□We belong□
□我們應該□
□我們應該在一起□
□We belong together□
哎，我誤判了這個湖的大小
Whew. Really misjudged the size of this lake.
為什麼她不直接從湖邊走過去
Why didn't she just walk around the lake?
胖艾米不做平凡事
Fat Amy doesn't do anything small.
是的，我一直在用我的拖鞋
Yes, I've been using my shower shoes.
好的，愛你，她在這裡
Okay, I love you, too. Here she is.
容剋夫人，怎麼樣
What up, Mrs. Junk?
□我們已經成為一種習慣□
□Have we become a habit□
□難道我們歪曲事實□
□Do we distort the facts□
□現在有沒有期待□
□Now there's no looking forward□
□現在有沒有回頭路可走□
□Now there's no turning back□
□當你說□
□When you say□
□去吧□
□Go□
繼續開啊!
Go!
呃，你到底在幹嘛?
Well, what are you doing?
我在這裡獨唱啊!
I'm soloing, here!
算了!
Whatever!
□我們屬於光線□
□We belong to the light□
□我們屬於雷□
□We belong to the thunder□
□我們屬於聲音□
□We belong to the sound of the words□
不!
No!
□我們都在墮落□
□We've both fallen under□
□哦□
□Oh□
□渦輪我們否認或擁抱□
□Whatever we deny or embrace□
□更好或更壞□
□For worse or for better□
□我們應該□
□We belong□
□我們應該在一起□
□We belong together□
□靠近你□
□Close your□
□閉上你的眼睛並嘗試睡覺□
□Close your eyes and try to sleep now□
□閉上眼睛試著做夢□
□Close your eyes and try to dream□
□理清思緒做到最好□
□Clear your mind and do your best□
□嘗試把這場面洗淨□
□To try and wash the palette clean□
□我們不能開始知道□
□We can't begin to know it□
□我們真正關心多少□
□How much we really care□
□我聽到你在我裡面的聲音□
□I hear your voice inside me□
□看到你的樣子無處不在□
□I see your face everywhere□
□你仍然說□
□Still you say□
□我們屬於光線□
□We belong to the light□
□我們屬於雷□
□We belong to the thunder□
好了，行了
Well, all right.
好吧，我們走，快進那個房子裡
All right, let's go. Into the house.
把脖子湊過來
Give me that neck.
我是說，我們可以...你想要...
I mean, we can do... Do you want it...
你是不是想把這些聲音分成不同的音階
Do you feel like you'd want to layer a bunch of voices?
我覺得在這裡一開始就肯定能做出來
I think in the beginning it could definitely build.
我覺得應該淡起
I think it starts out light, though.
然後緩緩的進入正曲
Get your cute butt in the studio, then.
順便說一句，別告訴我老闆，我們在這裡
Don't tell my boss that we were in here, by the way.
I got all I need when I got you and I
'Cause I look around me
and see a sweet life
'Cause I look around me and see a sweet life
這個...哇
This is... Wow!
這是真玩意
It's the real deal.
不要碰任何東西，艾米莉
Yeah, don't touch anything, Legacy.
你很漂亮，但是看起來笨手笨腳的
You're very pretty, but you seem clumsy.
很好
Great.
好吧
Okay.
Can't lie it's a sweet life
I'm stuck in the dark
but you're my flashlight
I'm stuck in the dark but you're my flashlight
You're getting me
Getting me through the night
You're getting me Getting me through the night
You're my flashlight
好的，這個是你創作的？
Okay, so you produced this?
嗯，是的，是艾米莉寫的
Uh, yes. Emily wrote it.
- 嗯嗯，誰是艾米莉？-我是
- Mmm-hmm. Who's Emily? - I am.
- 這位站在這裡的瘦高個- 嘿，艾米莉
- This tall drink of water, right there. - Hey. Emily.
好的...
Well...
呃...
Um...
我不...我不...我不喜歡這個
I don't... I don't... I don't like it.
我不喜歡的是你們能做到我能做到的事
What it is, is I don't like it when people can do what I can do.
某種意義還是那個說，這讓我受到威脅
You know, in a manner of speaking, it's threatening.
但是你們做到了
But, you just did it.
我有...
And I have a...
我這裡有幾點見解，希望你們能接受
I have a few notes that I assume that you're open to.
- 是的 - 呃，這是一張潛力十足的樣本唱片
- Yes. - Um, but this is a solid demo,
是實打實的
with real potential.
嗯，我期待與你們的合作
Yeah, I look forward to working together.
很高興見到你
It's nice to meet you.
- 你叫什麼？伊麗莎白？ - 艾米莉
- What is it? Elizabeth? - Emily.
- 艾米莉 - 伊麗莎白？艾米莉
- Emily. - Elizabeth? What?
- 艾米莉，謝謝 - 謝謝
- Emily. Thank you. - Thank you.
- 噢 - 我得馬上打個電話
- Oh. - I gotta jump on a call.
噢，不，這是
Yeah, no. No, get it in there. Get it in there. Attagirl.
- 來握手 - 對了
- You want one of these? - Oh, hey.
你想這樣？對了
You want one of those? There you go. Attagirl.
幹得好，瑞吉
Good job, Reggie.
我是瑞吉
I'm Reggie.
噢，天啊，我太緊張了，都不知道要說什麼了
Oh, my God, I was so nervous I didn't know what to say!
噢，我的天
Oh, my God!
你全身都是汗
You're all sweaty.
我們要遲到了
We're gonna be late!
不管有沒有你
We're taking the photo with or without you.
我們都要照相了！
We're taking the photo with or without you!
各位，靠近點，不不不，聚在一起
Everybody get together. No, no, no, together.
一二三，一輩子都是朋友的貝拉樂團
One, two, three! Bellas for life!
BGM：《Good Time》- Inna & Pitbull（專輯：Good Time）2014
哥本卡根機場
哥本哈根
哥德堡大學
卡姆維爾拉天空酒店
世界大賽舉辦地
克裡斯蒂安伯克王宮
斯塔恩博物館
蒂沃利公園
新港
好吧，這裡沒有一個餐廳提供
Okay. So, is there a restaurant in this town
除了魚以外的食物
that serves something other than fish?
我的確看到那邊有一個肯德基
I did see a KFC back there.
不，那裡也全都是魚，我看過了
Nope. All fish. I checked.
夥計們，在這邊，走這邊
Guys, over here. Come this way.
噢，克洛伊，我來了
Oh, Chloe, I'm coming for ya!
哇哦，畢業啦，放飛翅膀，耶！
Whoo-hoo. College graduates! Spreading my wings, y'all!
這裡有那麼多的丹麥人
There are so many fresh Danishes here.
我發誓，要不是我最佳定下來了
I swear, if I wasn't recently locked down,
我會撕一個洞貫穿整個城市
I would tear a hole through this city!
這個地方即難聞又下雨？
This place is so smelly and rainy.
為什麼美國人從不離開美國？
Why do Americans ever leave America?
因為文化，設計和歷史？
Culture, design, history.
我太喜歡這個地方了
I'm not copen-hating this place.
我餓死了
I'm starving.
為何我們不去參觀海登克裡斯蒂安安德森的家？
Yeah, why don't we go visit Hayden Christian Andersen's house?
那個傢伙？廢話連篇，總是對星球大戰前傳滔滔不絕
That guy? But he was pretty crap in the Star Wars prequels.
好了，我們到了
Well, here we are.
你們覺得這個舞台夠大嗎
Do you think the stage is big enough for what we want to do?
你在開玩笑嗎？簡直是巨大啊
You're kidding, right? It's huge.
你據的這個舞台可以了？
You guys think it'll work?
對我們來說夠了
It'll work for us. That's what matters.
走吧！
Let's go!
讓我們做好這次表演
Let's do this thing!
2015 世界阿卡貝拉大賽
哇呼！
Whoo!
大家都知道在哪裡碰面吧？
Everyone knows where to meet, right?
嗯，我們知道
Yeah, we know.
好的，注意安全，弗洛
All right. Safety first, Flo.
BGM：《Let's Go》-  Tiesto & Icona Pop（專輯：A Town Called Paradise）2014
就在這裡，或基本，所有的音樂大咖們
Here it is, folks. The granddaddy of them all.
世界阿卡貝拉冠軍賽
The World Championship of A Cappella!
今晚，來自世界各地的樂團蓄勢待發
Tonight, groups from around the globe duke it out
準備向世界冠軍杯發起衝擊
for the title of A-ca World Champion.
當然，代表美國的是陷入困境的巴頓貝拉樂團
And, of course, representing America, the embattled Barden Bellas.
貝拉樂團正在進行最後的嘗試通過成為第一支成為冠軍的
The Bellas, making one last attempt to repair a damaged legacy
美國團隊，來挽回她們的名譽
by becoming the first American team to claim the title.
約翰，你說她們會成功嗎？
Can they do it, John?
理論上講，可以，蓋爾
Theoretically, yes, Gail.
客觀來講，肯定不行了，在我看來，她們已經不行了
Realistically, absolutely not. Those girls are dead to me.
今晚這麼多國家代表隊匯聚在這裡，約翰
So many countries represented here tonight, John.
我們在綵排時看到了一個來自菲律賓的不可思議樂團
We saw in rehearsal an incredible group from the Philippines.
他們叫什麼？
What were they called?
人妖樂團
"The Ladyboys."
我想那不是他們的名字
That wasn't the name of the group, I don't think.
那是自我描述
I think that's how they described themselves.
沒錯，他們是「馬尼拉羨慕」樂團
That's right. They're "Manila Envy."
馬尼拉羨慕樂團
Manila Envy.
你知道，我在菲律賓的時候
You know, I spent some time with
曾經和一些人妖相處過
some ladyboys, uh, in the Philippines myself.
我不覺得很吃驚
Not surprising.
一群很有意思的年輕人
Very interesting young men.
用他們的嘴巴唱出美妙的歌
Doing amazing things with their mouths, I presume.
、當我們轉會到舞台上，我會在這裡用嘴巴給你做一些美妙的事
When we go back to the stage, I'll do a few for you here.
- 我們待會再說吧 - 好的
- Uh, you know, we can get to it, I think. - Okay.
也許能趁韓國樂團下場的時候
You know, maybe when the Koreans are out there,
因為沒有人關係韓國樂團
because no one cares about the Korean group.
我喜歡他們的燒烤
Love that barbeque.
你在這裡幹嘛？
What are you doing here?
噢，你...
Oh, you...
做一切支持貝拉樂團的工作
You know, anything to support the Bellas.
哇，我真是...
Wow. I...
現在輪到我說不出話來了
Now I'm the one who can't speak.
我緊張死了
I'm just so freaking nervous.
噢，天，別緊張
Oh, my God. Don't be.
你會表現的很好的
You'll be great.
我是說，聽說你們一周七天都在不停的練
I mean, we heard you guys rehearsing, like, 24/7.
我大概要去找找我的座位了
So I'll... I should probably go find my seat.
好
Yeah.
走之前，我...
But before I go, I just...
有東西給你
I have something for you.
噢...
Oh...
抱歉，我以為是一個不同的方向
I'm so sorry. I thought that that was going in a different direction.
- 我的錯 - 不，不，我很喜歡
- That's my bad. - No, no, I liked it.
艾米莉，準備好了嗎？
Em, you ready?
好了，我馬上到
Yeah. Yeah, I'll be right there.
本傑
Benji.
好的，祝你表演成功
Okay. Well, break a leg.
《Any Way You Want It》- Journey（專輯：Departure）2006
Pentatonix：簡稱PTX，純人聲樂團，翻唱流行歌曲成名
達斯發升級，加油！
DSM! Ja! DSM! Ja! DSM! Ja! DSM! Ja!
達斯發聲機，加油！達斯發聲機，加油！
DSM! Ja! DSM! Ja!
達斯發聲機，加油！
DSM! Ja!
- 哇- 幹得漂亮
- Ooh! - Well done!
到他們了，印度的烤餅車站樂團
There they go, the Indian group, the Naan-Stops,
走下舞台後會奪走我們的工作
running off stage to take a few more of our jobs.
我覺得那個小個子挺辣的
I thought the little one was spicy!
達斯發聲機，加油！
DSM! Ja! DSM! Ja!
接下來上場的是，達斯發聲機樂團
And coming up next, Das Sound Machine.
觀眾都愛他們，約翰
A crowd favorite, John.
達斯發聲機，加油
DSM! Ja! DSM! Ja! DSM! Ja!
你聽到了嗎
Hear that?
他們為我們歌頌
They chant. For us.
你們輸的時候不要哭的太慘
Now, don't cry too hard when you lose, huh?
那會讓你的眼睛腫起來的
Makes eyes puffy.
你的手真軟
Your hands are so soft.
對不起，我不懂失敗者的語言，你剛才說了什麼？
I'm sorry, I don't speak "loser." What did you say?
事實上她會說八種語言
She actually speaks eight languages,
但是失敗者語不是其中的一種
but "loser" is not one of them.
萬事必有終結的一天
Everything must come to an end.
就算是貝拉樂團也不例外
Even the Bellas.
保重，輸得好看一點
Take care and lose nice.
你的汗水有一股肉桂的香味
Huh, your sweat smells like cinnamon.
該死
Damn it!
...達斯發聲機樂團!
...Das Sound Machine!
《My Songs Know What You Did In The Dark》- Fall Out Boy（專輯：Save Rock And Roll）2013
DSM!
□暗影中中要小心祈禱□
□B-b-be careful making wishes in the dark, dark□
□很難保證他們在達成自己的願望後會給你兌現□
□Can't be sure when they've hit their mark□
□在最艱辛的日子裡□
□And besides in the meantime□
□我僅僅詛咒你被撕碎□
□I'm just dreaming of tearing you apart□
□我與惡魔站在同一立場□
□I'm in the details with the devil□
□所以在現在這個世界我已經勢不可擋□
□So world now can the never get me on my level□
□我想要幫你掙脫束縛□
□I just got to get you out the cage□
□化為戀人的怒火□
□I'm a young lovers rage□
□用烈焰將一切化作灰燼□
□Gonna need a spark to ignite□
□我的歌已唱罷黑夜中你經歷的一切！□
□My songs know what you did the in dark□
□所以拆穿它們□
□So light em up-up-up□
□點燃它們□
□Light em up-up-up□
□毀滅它們□
□以我的火之力□
□I'm on fire□
□所以拆穿它們□
□So light em up-up-up□
□點燃它們□
□Light em up-up-up□
□毀滅它們□
□以我的火之力□
□I'm on fire□
《All I Do Is Win》- DJ Khaled & T-Pain & Ludacri & Rick Ross & Snoop Dogg（專輯：Victory）2010
□DSM要記載在史詩上□
□DSM goin' in on the verse□
□因為他們從未被打敗□
□Cause they never been defeated□
□而去他們從未止步□
□On and they won't stop now□
□用你們的手把他們舉到天上□
□Get your hands up put 'em in the sky□
□人們被關住了□
□Folks locked down□
□每年賺幾百萬□
□Make millions every year□
□國際大賽冠軍□
□International champions□
□因為我們能做到□
□Cause all I do all I all I□
□我們能做的就是贏□
□All I all I do is win□
□嘿□
□Hey□
□贏沒有問題□
□Win no matter what□
□錢在我們腦中□
□Got money on my mind□
□因為我們永遠不嫌多□
□I can never get enough□
□每一次都在加快賺錢□
□And every time I step up in the building□
□每個人都馬不停蹄□
□Everybody hands go up□
□他們待在那裡□
□And they stay there□
□點燃他們□
□Light 'em up□
□他們待在那裡□
□And they stay there□
□毀滅它們□
□Light 'em up□
□他們待在那裡□
□And they stay there□
□點燃他們□
□Light 'em up up up□
□以我的火之力
□I'm on fire□
□因為我們能做的就是贏□
□Cause all I do is win win win□
□而去我們還會繼續□
□And if you're goin' in□
□把你的手舉在空中讓他們停留在那裡□
□Put your hands in the air make 'em stay there□
□點燃他們□
□Light' em up□
□讓他們呆在那裡□
□And they stay there□
□毀滅它們□
□Light 'em up□
□讓他們呆在那裡□
□And they stay there□
□拆穿他們□
□Light 'em up up up□
□以我的火之力□
□I'm on fire□
□因為我們能做的只是贏□
□Cause all I do is win win win□
□我們還會繼續□
□And if you're goin' in□
□把你們的手舉在空中□
□Put your hands in the air make 'em stay there
□點燃他們□
□So light 'em up up up□
□毀滅他們□
□Light 'em up up up□
□拆穿他們□
□以我的火之力□
□I'm on fire□
觀眾們為他們變得瘋狂
They've got the crowd going wild!
好了，開始吧
Okay, shake it off.
達斯發聲機 達斯發聲機
DSM! DSM!
達斯發聲機
Das Sound Machine.
這個德國樂團再次為我們呈現了精彩的表演
An incredible performance once again from the German group.
蓋爾，我跟你說
I'm telling you, Gail, though,
要是今晚貝拉樂團能像過去一樣發揮
if the Bellas of old show up tonight,
這可能成為歷史上美國和德國
this could be the most significant conflict
最重要的對決
between America and Germany in history.
多讀點書吧，約翰
Crack a book, John.
請把這些遞給你的朋友，謝謝
Pass one down to your friends. Here you go. Thank you.
好的，給你，夥計
All right, here you go, buddy.
謝謝，兄弟
Thanks, man.
你去哪裡了？
Where have you been?
兄弟，你絕對想不到
You have no idea, dude.
姐妹們，這是最後的表演
Final performance, guys.
我們要去戰勝達斯發聲機樂團
We need to get out there and beat DSM.
這是為了我們所有人
This one's for us.
姐妹們，外面那些憎恨我們的人
Guys, there's gonna be some haters out there.
一定會看著我們美國隊，說
They're gonna look at us, Team USA,
為什麼最有才的是那個澳大利亞人
and be like, "Why is the most talented one Australian?"
你猜怎麼著，我是胖，說一這就差不多了
Well, guess what. I am fat. So that is close enough.
我們要他們看看我們的本事
We are gonna show them who we are.
一群種族各異
A bunch of ethnically diverse,
且全是女性
for the most part feminine,
的驚艷歌手樂團！
amazing singers!
耶！
Yeah!
讓我們走出去，唱響全世界
Let's just go out there and ac' the world!
好！
Yes!
- 耶！- 沒錯！
- Yeah! - Yes!
約翰，這有可能是我們最後一次
John, it's possible we are watching
看見巴頓貝拉樂團的的歡呼了
the last hurrah of the Barden Bellas.
而去她們的奪冠之路會很艱難
It's going to be very hard to pull this off,
要是她們失敗了
and if they don't,
她們就無法參加阿卡貝拉比賽了
they are out of business as an a cappella group.
這就徹底完了
It is over.
好了，我們開始吧
All right! Let's do this!
巴頓大學貝拉樂團
...Barden University's Bellas!
- 加油 - 耶!
- Yes! - Whoo!
這才是我的女孩
That's my girl!
貝卡
Beca!
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run the world□
《Run The World (Girls)》- Beyonce（專輯：4）2011
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□We run this motha□
□Who run this motha□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run this motha□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run this motha□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run this motha□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□帶上它 寶貝 你所有的朋友□
□Hey bring it on baby all your friends□
《Where Them Girls At》- Flo Rida & Nicki Minaj（專輯：Nothing but the Beat）2011
□女生□
□Girls□
□你是肥胖型我喜歡這樣的□
□You're the ish and I love that body□
□你想要看我的球□
□You wanna ball explicit□
□我發誓我不會告訴別人□
□I swear you're good I won't tell nobody□
□你有一個寶貝臉我想看看□
□You got a BFF I wanna see that girl□
□所有的女士都被邀請了□
□It's all women invited□
□路易做了頭髮和指甲□
□Hair do's and nails that Louie□
□香奈兒在派對上□
□Chanel all up in the party□
□女孩在哪裡□
□Where dem girls at□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run this mother□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治這個世界□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□女孩在哪裡□
□Where dem girls at□
□女孩在□
□Girls at□
□女孩在那裡□
□女生□
□Girls□
□我們屬於光線□
□We belong to the light□
□我們屬於雷□
□We belong to the thunder□
□我們應該□
□We belong□
□我們應該在一起□
□We belong we belong together□
□我們應該□
□We belong□
□我們是誰□
□Who are we□
□我們統治□
□What we run□
□誰統治世界□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□誰統治世界□
□Who run the world□
□女生□
□Girls□
□我們應該□
□We belong□
□我們是誰□
□Who are we□
□誰統治世界□
□What do we run□
□We run the world□
□我們應該□
□We belong□
□當明天來臨時□
□When tomorrow comes□
□我將一己之力□
□I'll be on my own□
□害怕的感覺不斷湧來□
□Feeling frightened of the things□
□我不知道會發生什麼事□
□That I don't know□
□當明天來臨時 明天來臨時□
□When tomorrow comes when tomorrow comes□
□明天來臨時□
□雖然道路漫長□
□And though the road is long□
□我抬頭看向天空□
□I look up to the sky□
□我在黑暗中發現□
□Darkness all around□
□我停下腳步不動□
□I hope that I could fly□
她們是在唱一首原創歌曲嗎？
are doing an original song?
□然後唱起歌來□
□Then I sing along then I sing along□
□而我獨自歌唱 獨自歌唱 □
□當我有了你，我就像擁有一切□
□I got all I need when I got you and I□
□我環顧四周□
□Cause I look around me□
□而我看見了美滿的生活□
□And see a sweet life□
□我被困在黑暗中□
□I'm stuck in the dark□
□但你是我的照明燈□
□But you're my flashlight□
□你抓著我□
□You're gettin' me□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□Gettin' me through the night□
□我無法阻止我的心跳□
□You kick start my heart□
□當你閃耀在我的雙眼裡□
□When you're shinin' in my eyes□
□我不能說謊 因為這是一個甜蜜的生活□
□I can't lie it's a sweet life□
□我被困在黑暗中□
□I'm stuck in the dark□
□但你是我的照明燈□
□But you're my flashlight□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中 □
□You're gettin' me through the night□
看看這個
Look at this!
這看起來像是整個巴頓貝拉樂團
It looks like the Barden Bellas are being
數代的貝拉老成員加入了她們的表演
joined on stage by generations of Bellas,
□將我帶領出黑暗之中 □
□You're gettin' me through the night□
一切回到了開始的那一天
going all the way back to the beginning.
□因為你是我的光芒□
□Cause you're my flashlight□
□你是我的光芒□
□You're my flashlight□
□因為你是我的光芒□
□Cause you're my flashlight□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□You're gettin' me through the night□
□當我有了你，我就像擁有一切□
□I got all I need when I got you and I□
□我環顧四周□
□Cause I look around me□
□而我看見了美滿的生活□
□And see a sweet life□
□我被困在黑暗中□
□I'm stuck in the dark□
□但你是我的照明燈□
□But you're my flashlight□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□You're gettin' me through the night□
□我無法阻止我的心跳□
□You kickstart my heart□
□當你閃耀在我的雙眼裡□
□When you're shinin' in my eyes□
□我不能說謊 因為這是個甜蜜的生活□
□I can't lie it's a sweet life□
□我被困在黑暗中□
□I'm stuck in the dark□
□但你是我的照明燈□
□But you're my flashlight□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□You're getting me through the night□
□因為你是我的光芒□
□Cause you're my flashlight cause you are□
□Cause you're my flashlight□
□因為你是我的光芒□
□你是我的光芒□
□You're my flashlight□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□You're gettin' me through the night□
□因為你是我的光芒□
□Oh cause you're my flashlight□
□因為你是我的□
□Cause you're my□
□將我帶領出黑暗之中□
□Gettin' me through the night□
"單純的" "不成熟" "脆弱的" "無遮掩的"
"Simple," "raw," "vulnerable," "exposed."
蓋爾，這讓我回想到了許多，但是容許我再加一個
I've been called a lot of things, Gail. But let me add one more.
我被打動了
I'm impressed.
我還以為你會說「同性戀般的快樂」
I thought you were gonna say "gay."
- 艾米莉 - 耶！
- Emily! - Yeah!
艾米莉
Emily!
艾米莉 艾米莉
Emily! Emily!
嗚呼!  哇!
Whoo! Whoo!
貝拉樂團 貝拉樂團 貝拉樂團
Bellas! Bellas! Bellas!
噢，她們打動了這裡的每一個人
Oh. They have touched every person here.
我也被打動了，約翰
They've touched me, John.
這樣，蓋爾，每個人都碰過你
Well, everyone has touched you, Gail,
但是我們談論的是一些別的東西
but this is something else.
這是儀式用的
It's ceremonial,
你肯定不應該喝它，因為這基本就是毒藥
and you should definitely not drink it 'cause it is essentially poison.
- 真難喝 - 好吧
- Terrible for you. - Okay.
- 好吧 - 棒極了
- Okay. - Great.
噢，這聞起來像是櫻桃混合香草
Ooh. It smells like cherries and vanilla.
好了，跟我說
Okay, repeat after me.
"我..." 然後唱你的名字
"I..." Sing your name.
我...
I...
艾米莉...
Emily...
好了
Okay.
"我發誓會永遠秉持貝拉樂團的信念"
"Promise to uphold the ideals of a Bella woman forever."
我發誓會永遠秉持貝拉樂團的信念
Promise to uphold the ideals of a Bella woman forever.
好了，這就是最後的宣講儀式了
And that's it. That's the end of the speech.
沒有什麼其他古怪的儀式
Nothing weird happens after that.
給些給你
These are for you.
還有，別去地下室，那裡鬧鬼
Don't go in the basement, it's haunted.
等等!
Wait!
最後一件事
One last thing.
對的，每個貝拉新成員必須從這個樓梯滑下來
Yes, every Bella must christen the house
以作為新人的洗禮
by sliding down the staircase.
你是認真的?
Seriously?
- 這是傳統 - 沒錯
- It's tradition. - Yeah.
別擔心，我示範給你看
Don't worry. I'll show you.
看著啦
Behold!
裝得真爽.
Crushed it.
姿勢不錯
Good form.
我現在準備好向前看了
Now I'm ready to move on.
後代，到你了
Legacy, you're up.
好的，我準備好了
All right, I'm ready.
開始吧
Let's do this!
《Crazy Youngsters》- Ester Dean（專輯：Pitch Perfect 2）2015
《All Of Me》- John Legend（專輯：Love in the Future）2013
What would I do without your smart mouth
Drawing me in, and you kicking me out
You've got my head spinning, no kidding
I can't pin you down
太棒了
Yes!
My head's under water
But I'm breathing fine
你不能
You can't!
你不能轉回去，這不符合規矩
You can't turn back around. That's not part of the rules! That's not...
有那麼糟？
That bad?
'Cause all of you
Loves all of me
Love your curves and all your edges
太感謝你了，法拉爾
Thank you so much, Pharrell.
Perfect imperfections
Give your all to me
I'll give my all to you
亞當，轉過來
Adam, turn around!
每個人都這樣做，他們愛我
Everybody's doing it, baby! They love me!
美國愛我
America loves me!
Give your all to me
I'll give my all to you
我把我自己獻給你
And I give myself to you!
給你！給你！給你！
And you! And you! And you!
還有你，美國！
And you, America!
哇!
Whoo!
- 嘿，兄弟 - 是的，布萊克
- Hey, man. - Yes. Yes, Blake.
你叫什麼名字
What's your name, brother?
我現在不知道
I don't even know right now!
嘿，夥計，幫我個忙
Hey, just do me a favor, man.
無論什麼情況，都不要選我當你的教練
Please, under no circumstances, choose me for your coach.
- 我只是想表達我的想法 - 好的
- I just want to put that out there. - Okay.
你很有個性，我喜歡
So, you have a lot of personality. And I love that.
謝謝
Thank you.
你很有趣，我能和有趣的人共事
You're interesting, and I can work with interesting.
在所有的教練中
All of the coaches at my disposal,
我選擇的是...
I'm gonna have to choose
克裡斯提那
Christina!
哇!
Whoo!
耶!
Yay!
太棒了!
This is awesome!
- 非常感謝你 - 客氣了
- Thank you so much. - You're welcome.
噢，我的天
Oh, my God.
哇 ! 好了，好了，好了
Whoa! Okay, okay, okay.
- 謝謝你 - 好了
- Thank you. - Okay.
真的太感謝你了
Thank you so much.
啊哈! 好夥伴!
Aah! Besties!
嗨，媽媽，嗨
Hey, Mom! Hey.
嘿,  艾米!
Hey, Amy!
感謝觀看